<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/poem/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/poem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Identity</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2016/04/my-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2016/04/my-identity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few words dedicated to people who made me who I am right now, my teachers. I know few of them personally and few others I am yet to meet in person. But they are still there always for me. Guiding me and helping me whenever and wherever I need. Words are not enough to say Thanks but still here with my small try&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is original Gujarati Version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;જેને કોઈ ઓળખની જરૂર નથી&lt;br /&gt;
જેની પ્રતિષ્ઠા ચંદ્રની જેમ વિશ્વમાં વ્યાપ છે&lt;br /&gt;
એવા અર્જુનની ઓળખ પૂછી કોઈએ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ના કીધું એણે કે હું અર્જુન&lt;br /&gt;
ના કીધું સર્વશ્રેષ્ઠ ધનુર્ધર&lt;br /&gt;
ના કીધું પાંડવ ના કોન્તેય&lt;br /&gt;
ના કહ્યું એણે કે મારી ઓળખ તો મારા દસ નામ&lt;br /&gt;
ના કૃષ્ણનો મિત્ર કહ્યો, ના ઇન્દ્ર નો વંશજ&lt;br /&gt;
ના એની ઓળખ ગાંડીવે આપી, ના પાશુપત અસ્ત્રએ&lt;br /&gt;
હર સમય હર સંજોગમાં એણે એજ કહ્યું કે&lt;br /&gt;
હું મારા ગુરુનો શિષ્ય અને એજ મારી ઓળખ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;એ અર્જુન તો મોટોભા થયો&lt;br /&gt;
એની સામે મારી શું વિસાત ને શું ઓળખ&lt;br /&gt;
પણ મને જો કોઈ મારી ઓળખ પૂછી લો&lt;br /&gt;
તો હું ભી એજ કહું કે&lt;br /&gt;
હું મારા ગુરુનો શિષ્ય અને એજ મારી ઓળખ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here it is, in English (courtesy Dharman Dave)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need an introduction&lt;br /&gt;
He whose prestige is known to the world like the moon&lt;br /&gt;
Someone asked that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arjuna&#34;&gt;Arjun&lt;/a&gt; his identity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither did he say I am (the famous) Arjun&lt;br /&gt;
Nor did he say I am the great archer (best of the best)&lt;br /&gt;
Neither did he say he was the son of Pandu&lt;br /&gt;
Nor the son of Kunti&lt;br /&gt;
He also didn’t say, “My identity is my ten names”&lt;br /&gt;
Neither did he say, “I’m a friend of (Lord) Krishna’s“&lt;br /&gt;
Nor a descendent of (God) Indra
Neither was he identified by Gandiv (indestructible bow)&lt;br /&gt;
Nor by the Pashupat weapon (destroyer arrow)&lt;br /&gt;
Every time and under all circumstances he said the same thing,&lt;br /&gt;
“I am a student of my teacher and that is my only identity”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Arjun is a legend&lt;br /&gt;
I am nothing compared to him, so is my identity&lt;br /&gt;
But if someone asks for my identity&lt;br /&gt;
I would also say the exact same thing,&lt;br /&gt;
“I am a student of my teacher and that is my only identity”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey in Search of Destination</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/03/journey-in-search-of-destination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/03/journey-in-search-of-destination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never thought I would make this public. I wrote long back for one of my dear cousin. It was relevant then. But it is more relevant now. One of my best friend, batch mate, college mate, colleague at one point of time, rommie is now moving to another country. With a aim to never looking back for all the good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nrezzzz&#34;&gt;Andrew Vyas&lt;/a&gt; this is for you. You are one of the friend I never wanted because I knew one day time flew and you or me will move on and that may be good for future but at point it is utterly painful. Pain that can&amp;rsquo;t be defined by words my friend. But still here are few words&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मंजिल की तलाश में दूर हम निकल गए
रस्ते बनते गए हमराही मिलते गए
मंजिल तोह आज भी दूर है
मंजिल के लिए प्यार भी  वही है
लेकिन पता नहीं क्यों रस्ते इतने अच्छे क्यों है
आँखे इतनी नर्म क्यों है
मंजिल पाने की चाह तो आज भी वही है
हमराही को छोड़ने का गम क्यों है
हमराही कल भी बिछड़े थे, आज भी बिछड़ रहे है
लेकिन दील मे एक सन्नाटा, तन्हाई, दर्द आज ही क्यों है
मंजिल की तलाश में हम तो फीर भी निकल चले है
रस्ते फीर बनते चले है, हमराही फीर मिलते चले है
लेकिन दील मै उनकी याद क्यों है, ये दर्द एक बेचैनी सि क्यों है&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For people who don&amp;rsquo;t understand Hindi, here is English translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In search of destination we came long way
roads started carving them selves, new companion started joining me
destination is still far
love for destination is still there
but don&amp;rsquo;t know why roads seems more beautiful
and have tears at the corner of my eyes
Desire to get to the destination is still the same
then why there is pain for leaving companion back
I left companion and I am leaving companion back
then why there is silence, loneliness and pain in heart
Still moving on in search of destination
roads are being made again, companion are started joining again
then why there are memories them of who left behind, why there is pain, restlessness in heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear friend wherever you go my wishes and prayers are always there for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I continue writing more poems?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/should-i-continue-writing-more-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/should-i-continue-writing-more-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long back I have tried my hand to writing poems. And trust me I am no where near poetic part. I have good grip over language but that is only for my mother tongue. I am quite comfortable with English but still no where near having artistic touch. Or in simple language my database of words is not that strong. But normally I am able to convey my feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say, I am pretty lucky in the case of writing poems. Though I have write only few, many of them got good review from whom so ever read it. But that charm doesn&amp;rsquo;t last that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a poem for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/&#34;&gt;sister&lt;/a&gt; and it don&amp;rsquo;t get any kind of review. I do got personal message from sister after a long time that &amp;ldquo;it was sweet&amp;rdquo;. But that all because she is my sister. Personally if I like to give review to my this poem it is not good at all. There are tsunami of feeling I wanted to convert and I just converted drops of it. And at that moment I decided, will never write poem; at least never in public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do write sometimes, but that is all personal on personal request. And I will not say that poem too. They are just few lines, I crafted for person requested. Like few hand picked words, that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But over the time I got request to write more poems. So, I decided to take a course at &lt;a href=&#34;https://class.coursera.org/songwriting-004&#34;&gt;coursera&lt;/a&gt; and with that I like to take opinion of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should I write more poems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please write whatever you think in comments. And help me to make a decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Miss You Sister</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First friend I found was you&lt;br /&gt;
First enemy I found was you&lt;br /&gt;
First fight I had was with you&lt;br /&gt;
First person I always miss is you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beating me was your favorite game&lt;br /&gt;
Teasing me with different names&lt;br /&gt;
Remaining is now, only the pain&lt;br /&gt;
Not being with you, I feel mundane&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are Dad’s favorite&lt;br /&gt;
You are Mom’s favorite&lt;br /&gt;
But you know you are also my favorite&lt;br /&gt;
Then why you became someone else’s favorite&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Achievements are just made for you&lt;br /&gt;
Success always waiting for you&lt;br /&gt;
Even world is following you&lt;br /&gt;
But you know at home, someone still waiting for you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You went to school made new friends&lt;br /&gt;
You went to college made new friends&lt;br /&gt;
I go to school, you are my friend&lt;br /&gt;
I go to college, you are my friend&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you want to shine and never fade&lt;br /&gt;
Want to study and always be ahead&lt;br /&gt;
Want to work hard and move forward&lt;br /&gt;
But once look back, and then move forward&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time doesn’t stop, neither do you&lt;br /&gt;
You are busy with time for only few&lt;br /&gt;
I am still at doorstep, eagerly waiting for you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got married, had a new life&lt;br /&gt;
Few more smiles because of you,&lt;br /&gt;
A new sunrise shines your new life&lt;br /&gt;
But what will I do without you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life is incomplete without you&lt;br /&gt;
My poem is incomplete without you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>