<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/web/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Angularjs and the Mess we are in</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;Angularjs&lt;/a&gt;?!? Everyone worked is web, mobile, server, windows, mac, Linux, Google, Microsoft or anyway related to this knows about it. And its fun when people tell me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know about angularjs. Its pretty hot now a days. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to learn it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh man&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok I am no expert here in Angularjs. And I prefer not to be expert with any framework. Be it anything. But you know there is another &lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34;&gt;Angularjs&lt;/a&gt; from another universe. If you are learning (like seriously) then go for this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But be sure. There is a chance you will be inviting a hell of mess. I have been working with angular since last 3+ year. Either leading a team or part of team. And one thing I learn hard way. You need a discipline when you are working with JavaScript. But you need discipline of delta forces when you are working with angularjs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As metioned in site it is a superhero. And like every superhero it also should have responsiblitiy. But angular is abusing JavaScript every way possible. If something is possible that doesn&amp;rsquo;t means we should be doing it. We have damn book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596517748.do&#34;&gt;JavaScript: Good Parts&lt;/a&gt; all about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It called Good Parts means you just use Good Parts and leave bad one alone. But with angular it is like you are leaving in Bar and told not to touch Alcohol. On top of it you have &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.untappdllc.app&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;untapped&lt;/a&gt; installed in your mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why this? Lets take things one by one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope-poor-man-s-global&#34;&gt;Scope - Poor man&amp;rsquo;s global&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should not use global. That is proven truth. No, doubt in it. But what about &lt;strong&gt;We love &lt;em&gt;global&lt;/em&gt; so much.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got scope then. JSLint can&amp;rsquo;t catch it and we still have it. Now, angular lover may argue that we should not use it. But how can you prevent it from using it. It all comes to putting as rule in project wiki or training. But there is no way to prevent it. At least I don&amp;rsquo;t know one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;magical-directives&#34;&gt;Magical- Directives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you start abusing Angularjs people comes up with &lt;code&gt;But we have Directives?!?&lt;/code&gt; that magically solves everything. The problem with that it is hiding too much. Its good if things works out but when it breaks. Oh man. &lt;em&gt;You seriously wish that never happen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you still like Directives try implement two directive on one. It will be too much fun. And pure magic if one directive is created by you and other is created by third third-party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-musketeers-service-factory-and-provider&#34;&gt;Three musketeers - Service, Factory and Provider&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many times I have searched google with &lt;code&gt;Service vs Factor vs Provider&lt;/code&gt; . Nowadays you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to put angularjs on top of that. If you write above message you will have angularjs answer only. It way too complicated for simple module with helper functions. Aren&amp;rsquo;t we all happy with few base global in age of JQuery that passed in as parameter in modular functions. And now we have DI(Proudly called as Dependancy Injection).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wired-di&#34;&gt;Wired - DI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is good thing. A good thing invented from the object-oriented concept. And then it is used almost every where. whether it is needed or not. For the case of Angular it is good we can have module without worrying about modules. Directly available in function. But then what about other libraries we need to created wrapper around it to make angular way. And then have plenty of gulp or grunt plumbing tools so you can save your ass when things minified and combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grass-is-always-green-on-other-side&#34;&gt;Grass is always green on other side&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t say angular beast we never wanted. But you need to use it carefully. I have seen more than enough projects, new and legacy using angular in all wrong way. It make tough to debug or extend. Every time you got feeling that lets dump it all and make it again. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to learn another framework just learn &lt;code&gt;JavaScript - Good Parts&lt;/code&gt;. And things are all good. But instead most of resources are wasted on teaching Angularjs. With a hope that &lt;strong&gt;Super Hero&lt;/strong&gt; framework will solve every issue we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not going to be. It was never going to be. It will never going to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the one who gonna solve our issue. Pick your framework wisely and try not to hope so much from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-personal-pick&#34;&gt;My Personal Pick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to go so hard on my self and don&amp;rsquo;t want any error in my &lt;strong&gt;to be&lt;/strong&gt; big project. I will choose &lt;a href=&#34;http://elm-lang.org&#34;&gt;elm&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not framework but a hell of a language with crazy html support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people are coming from JavaScript land to join me then I ll go for &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/react/&#34;&gt;react&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a need quick two-way binding on a single page then &lt;a href=&#34;http://knockoutjs.com/&#34;&gt;knockout&lt;/a&gt; is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to go fast for small project. And I am the only one working on it at least for now. Or may be some single person working on it. I will go with Angularjs. I don&amp;rsquo;t mind. It is quick and easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big project. &lt;a href=&#34;http://emberjs.com/&#34;&gt;Ember&lt;/a&gt; is there. But few times I feel it is unnecessary complexity. Two way binding and not much of angular mess &lt;a href=&#34;http://aurelia.io/&#34;&gt;Aurelia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all opinion is derived from my personal experience and not influenced by any one. And it is my own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typed Hack of Cloudant using F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a continues war between typed and untyped data. But then there is need of finding a middle ground for ever growing application. There is place, a requirement when I feel application should be typed and data store should be untyped. So, I created this little code snippet to access cloudant (a couchbase fork) NOSQL database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was knowing about &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudant.com&#34;&gt;Cloudant&lt;/a&gt; from long back. Even before IBM bought it. It is indeed a wonderful service and also kinda free for small stuff. I thought this will be best fit for now. (I still don&amp;rsquo;t know why I didn&amp;rsquo;t use Mongodb).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As there is no need of scary relations ships with database. So, I decided to use this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now as one problem is solved other started. It is saving data that is in JSON format. That is untyped and F# is statically typed. I have tried few libraries developed in C# but was not happy. So, I thought it is just a HTTP request, why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t I give it as shot to make one of my own helper module? It is may be some what dirty attempt but I got it working what I needed with less than 100 lines. Here is code snippets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#r &amp;quot;../packages/Http.fs.1.4.0/lib/net40/HttpClient.dll&amp;quot;
#r &amp;quot;../packages/Newtonsoft.Json.6.0.6/lib/net45/Newtonsoft.Json.dll&amp;quot;

open HttpClient
open Newtonsoft.Json
open Newtonsoft.Json.Linq

[&amp;lt;CLIMutableAttribute&amp;gt;]
type Row&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt; = 
    { id : string
      key : string
      value : &#39;a }

[&amp;lt;CLIMutableAttribute&amp;gt;]
type ResultSet&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt; = 
    { total_rows : int
      offset : int
      rows : Row&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt; [] }

[&amp;lt;CLIMutableAttribute&amp;gt;]
type PostResult = 
    { ok : string
      id : string
      rev : string }

[&amp;lt;CLIMutableAttribute&amp;gt;]
type PostError = 
    { error : string
      reason : string }

let cloudantUrl = @&amp;quot;&amp;lt;cloudanturl/databasename/&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
let username = @&amp;quot;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
let password = @&amp;quot;&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;&amp;quot;

let private cloudantGet url = 
    let request = 
        createRequest Get url
        |&amp;gt; withBasicAuthentication username password
        |&amp;gt; withHeader (ContentType &amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;)
    request |&amp;gt; getResponseBody

let private cloudantPost url data = 
    let request = 
        createRequest Post url
        |&amp;gt; withBasicAuthentication username password
        |&amp;gt; withBody data
        |&amp;gt; withHeader (ContentType &amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;)
    request |&amp;gt; getResponseBody

let private checkDataForNewId (data : JObject) = 
    let removeIdrev (data : JObject) = 
        data.Remove(&amp;quot;_id&amp;quot;) |&amp;gt; ignore
        data.Remove(&amp;quot;_rev&amp;quot;) |&amp;gt; ignore
    if System.String.IsNullOrEmpty(data.[&amp;quot;_id&amp;quot;].ToString()) || System.String.IsNullOrEmpty(data.[&amp;quot;_rev&amp;quot;].ToString()) then 
        removeIdrev data
    data

let PostJson&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt; data = 
    let serializedObject = JObject.FromObject(data) |&amp;gt; checkDataForNewId
    serializedObject.Add(&amp;quot;$doctype&amp;quot;, JToken.Parse(&amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot; + data.GetType().Name + &amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot;))
    cloudantPost cloudantUrl &amp;lt;| serializedObject.ToString()

let GetJsonByType&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt; = 
    let resultset = 
        JsonConvert.DeserializeObject&amp;lt;ResultSet&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
            (cloudantGet (cloudantUrl + &amp;quot;/_design/Type/_view/&amp;quot; + typeof&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt;.Name))
    query { 
        for row in resultset.rows do
            select row.value
    }

let GetJsonById&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt; Id = JsonConvert.DeserializeObject&amp;lt;&#39;a&amp;gt;(cloudantGet (cloudantUrl + Id))

[&amp;lt;CLIMutableAttribute&amp;gt;]
type Person = 
    { _id : string
      _rev : string
      FirstName : string
      LastName : string }

let newPerson = 
    { _id = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
      _rev = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
      FirstName = &amp;quot;Boom&amp;quot;
      LastName = &amp;quot;Baam&amp;quot; }

let inline isNull (x:^a when ^a : not struct) =
    obj.ReferenceEquals (x, Unchecked.defaultof&amp;lt;_&amp;gt;)

let findPerson = 
    query { 
        for p in GetJsonByType&amp;lt;Person&amp;gt; do
            where (p.FirstName = &amp;quot;Boom&amp;quot;)
            select p
            headOrDefault
            }
isNull findPerson    
GetJsonById&amp;lt;Person&amp;gt; (&amp;quot;3b389dc6b8ee0dcbf7f366faaa59cf42&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In above code below part is just for testing. And even with that code snippet is 98 lines. So, with blank line removed it is even short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in cloudant I need to create views so its code is like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;function(doc) {
    if (doc.$doctype !== &amp;quot;Person&amp;quot;) return;
    var copydoc = JSON.parse(JSON.stringify(doc));
    delete copydoc[&amp;quot;$doctype&amp;quot;];
    emit(doc._id,copydoc);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need &lt;code&gt;$doctype&lt;/code&gt; while I am inserting or updating data only, not while reading. So, I am removing it. As I am already filtering based on type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In above code two libraries are getting used one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/relentless/Http.fs&#34;&gt;Http.fs&lt;/a&gt; and the other is &lt;a href=&#34;http://james.newtonking.com/json&#34;&gt;JSON.net&lt;/a&gt; libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In library as you can see I am not doing anything special. I am inserting data with type information. If new data is there I am removing &lt;code&gt;_id&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;_rev&lt;/code&gt; and for simplicity sake I had put &lt;code&gt;_id&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;_rev&lt;/code&gt; in all the types I am using to interacting with Cloudant data store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now whenever I am reading I just need to give type and that will be fetched as collection of that typed records. And once collection came to memory now I have powerful F# to process data. In above code I am using &lt;code&gt;query&lt;/code&gt; expression to do so. It becomes very easy and fun to use. And it is damn fast. At least for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t know it if perfect or not. It kinda part functional and part Object Oriented as far as I know. Should I convert this to Type Provider or is it possible or not? I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But one thing is sure I am achieving what I wanted with simplest possible code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear F# community members&lt;/strong&gt; do provide your views on this. And also let me know if it will be use full to make it more mature and push it as nuget package. Or may be a type provider for Cloudant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dmohl&#34;&gt;Daniel Mohl&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; old library &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dmohl/FSharpCouch&#34;&gt;FSharpCouch&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sails sailing seamlessly on Azure Web Sites</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodeframework.com/&#34;&gt;frameworks&lt;/a&gt; for web development in &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodejs.org/&#34;&gt;Nodejs&lt;/a&gt;. Many of them are pretty cool. I pretty much like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sailsjs.org/#/&#34;&gt;SailsJS&lt;/a&gt;. And also have worked on that in recent past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when it comes to hosting I love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; for various reasons. It is specially awesome when it comes to web sites. You do some experiments and throw it towards azure and that is ready for world to check out. My many experiments with &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/category/functional-web/&#34;&gt;F# and Web&lt;/a&gt; are already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I was talking with a friend about SailsJS and discussion kinda stuck at deployment part. As it is having kinda manual process involved. It is never a issue to fire a few commands but even why I should waste few key strokes when that can be done by Azure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always a fan of continues integration and continues delivery mechanism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched Google to find out if anyone has done this before. Results showing couple of examples; but all with spinning up VM on Azure and hosting a application. But I think that is to a overkill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried &lt;code&gt;sails new&lt;/code&gt; and put a web.config file in root folder and try to published it with web matrix. And web site crashed. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I still don&amp;rsquo;t recall when things just run without crashing at first shot with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see the streaming log (&lt;em&gt;console.log in nodejs case&lt;/em&gt;) with &lt;code&gt;azure site log tail &amp;lt;sitename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and found out that it is not getting node modules. That is weird as I was pushing npm_modules too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I tried with github repository. And that thing just worked. Without any issue and also directly in production mode. (&lt;em&gt;I seriously don&amp;rsquo;t know how it switched to production mode. As for production mode I need to pass parameter &amp;ndash;prod with app.js&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to change server.js to app.js in web.config. I guess it is kinda required. I am also skipping npm_modules with gitignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now first page is running without any issue. So, now it is time to sailing on azure web sites with sailsjs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;a href=&#34;http://sailslift.azurewebsites.net/&#34;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; and my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjee17/sailslift&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to clone and give PR with some demo application. I seriously like to see how far it can go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if any further details are required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failed attempt to write series, again!</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have tried writing complete series again. And again failed. And I am stopping it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are couple of reason of it. First and for most thing is I am not good at it. No where near even readable, I guess. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t know reason specifically for that. May be I can write on specific topic better instead of things that are continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is the reason complete series thing is not that good but individual write ups are getting good reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one more things. Few things are just very random that can&amp;rsquo;t fit in series at all. Few days back I was trying to run SignalR with F#. I succeeded but that will not fit here. Before that there was article about &lt;a href=&#34;2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/&#34;&gt;getting started with Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; from very zero. And that also can&amp;rsquo;t fit here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I finally though to kill it for while. Because of this I couldn&amp;rsquo;t able to write few other things I like to write. I am putting this in this series as completely non-technical part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be more articles about web, game and F# but not in series form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, wait for next one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Servicestack meet F# via Side Waffle</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have specific love for &lt;a href=&#34;http://servicestack.net/&#34;&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; and that is known thing. It is not because it is awesome or the ways it do web service things, no one else is doing. But because of my past with WCF. It is so rocky that I never want to go back.  And more over &lt;a href=&#34;http://servicestack.net/&#34;&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; doing hell lot of the things under the cover, and that is also without doing any damn thing into &lt;strong&gt;XML&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell, yes.. No XML&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I can write on and on for &lt;a href=&#34;http://servicestack.net/&#34;&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; but for now it is not the topic. Topic is about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/YakShavingDefinedIllGetThatDoneAsSoonAsIShaveThisYak.aspx&#34;&gt;Shaving the Yak&lt;/a&gt;. There are many hatters of Visual Studio and its project file. I also don&amp;rsquo;t mind sometimes joining the league. But for most of the cases it is doing many things, that we need to do otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I am saying this because I have done this while creating templates for  &lt;a href=&#34;http://servicestack.net/&#34;&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt;. My first experience is damn flow less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created one sample application and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielmohl.com/&#34;&gt;Daniel Mohl&lt;/a&gt; did the mojo jojo part. And template is up and running. But after that he was little bit busy with day job so I got that task. And first challenge was to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://servicestack.net/&#34;&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; with F#. Console application is pretty easy as I have done it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjee17/ServiceStackHeroku&#34;&gt;earlier too&lt;/a&gt; and deployed it to &lt;a href=&#34;http://servicestackheroku.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;. But with Asp.Net it was giving weird issue. After struggling for two weeks and asking community over twitter, I got answer from &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/21213363/servicestack-razor-page-is-getting-added-to-content&#34;&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;. Damn silly mistake. I copy pasted code from self host and that is spinning up two server. Once solved I was so happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But next thing is waiting for me is to make is template. I was having no idea how to do that. Other than I was having link where to give pull request. At this point &lt;a href=&#34;http://sidewaffle.com/&#34;&gt;Side Waffle&lt;/a&gt; came to rescue. Just a 5 minutes video and you are done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I do got some hiccups, like I was unable to created project at first. But then I did &lt;em&gt;hacking&lt;/em&gt; , lamest one. Did copy paste of other working project, removed their data and insert mine. And it was working.  Obviously this was not the best way but for now it is working. And I am the happy one for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I have given my first pull request to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;F# Community&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; project. Yes, Yes, Yes&amp;hellip; It is time for celebration. This can not be possible without a wonderful helping community over github, twitter, stackoverflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But two things are certain from my experience that Yak Shaving is pain in a##, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://sidewaffle.com/&#34;&gt;Side Waffle&lt;/a&gt; is flow less in saving it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will highly encourage people having .Net Open Source project, please do make template and provide the boiler plate code. It will be hell easy to get started in that way. And it will save time from doing initial set up to get up and started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;  Currently I am putting together V4 templates at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjee17/ServiceStackFSharp&#34;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;.  And again facing issue to make Asp.Net version running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am waiting for my pull request to get accepted. Once done, do have a look. You will see that F# and Servicestack are made for each other. Both are strongly typed, believed in message driven design and async model of working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In current state where everyone is making API, this is most &lt;em&gt;viable&lt;/em&gt; option for .Net people to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Template is currently having V3.71, it is still under MIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if someone like to move to V4, that is also not that costly option for the worth Servicestack bringing to development. Once I ll get up and running V4, I will put the template of that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community members, if there are any suggestion, comments please do provide. And obviously I am happy to take pull request for my template projects too. Different combinations of Servicestack option will be great. Also, if someone can check out issue that will be also great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update2:&lt;/strong&gt;  Latest template is up at &lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/278caff1-917a-4ac1-a552-e5a2ce0f6e1f&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Gallery&lt;/a&gt;, now having asp.net host too. There are three additional templates. And also V4 issue is solved and project is working now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks F#, Servicestack and specially Side Waffle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.Net MVC5 with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielmohl.com/&#34;&gt;Danial Mohl&lt;/a&gt; getting started with Asp.net MVC5 is pretty easy. He had put a tremendous effort to make different kind of templates. Even starting from MVC3 till date now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old templates are like there are two projects one is C# and one is &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;. C# is having all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt;, html, css and stuff while F# is having coding part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with time pass and version update, now we are having pure F# templates. A single project of F# having code, Java Script, cshtml, html, CSS everything. It is far more fun and easy to get started with. At the end of day F# is all about compressing code. Doing more with less code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala people, play is almost same as MVC framework. If you are following, code will be almost same only. I will still try to put code snippets wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t downloaded template yet. Please check out my previous post the first one in series and download template. Once installed you are up and running to write some MVC code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am assuming that people trying this; is quite familiar with MVC and other concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I will be doing one to one map between C# and F# code. Just to get familiar with syntax. Then will move to optimized code to make it more functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note&lt;/strong&gt; If you are not having Visual Studio Pro or higher one. Do not worry, templates are working with Express versions also. As per latest release F# is now primarily supported by &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org/use/windows/&#34;&gt;Desktop and Web Express version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install template, create new project with MVC5 and Web API option. Hit F5 and it is done. You are up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling great?!? It is just started.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://kunjan.in/images/rollercoasterride.gif&#34; alt=&#34;roller coaster ride&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Functional web</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am doing web development from quite a long time. And now a days I am keep pushing my self to do functional programming. &lt;a href=&#34;http://learnyouahaskell.com/&#34;&gt;Learning&lt;/a&gt; languages like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.haskell.org/haskellwiki/Haskell&#34;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scala-lang.org/&#34;&gt;Scala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org/&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously I try my hand to other functional languages too as per time permits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I am .Net developer my primary focused is working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org/&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; and I will also start from that only. You can also check out other functional articles of mine to check out what I think about functional programming and why it is necessity now a days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org/&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; for a long is treated as second class citizen in main stream programming in .Net area. But now it is picking up the pace. When I decided to write a complete series of web development with I was even thinking like that only. There will be C# project and &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org/&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; project. C# project will take care of UI and F# project will do all the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But thanks to wonderful community of &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org/&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;, we have now pure templates. And that is the point of start. Complete web development using &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org/&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; only. Nothing can be more fun that this. And it is not ended here, there are testing , mocking , testing libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this series, I will try to check out every vertical of web development. Including deployment to cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also make sure to keep posting details about Scala and &lt;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; too, in compare to &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with &lt;strong&gt;Hello World&lt;/strong&gt;. Go to the visual studio gallery and download the templates and add-on for &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/278caff1-917a-4ac1-a552-e5a2ce0f6e1f&#34;&gt;Servicestak&lt;/a&gt; (Update is coming soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/b55b8aac-b11a-4a6a-8a77-2153f46f4e2f&#34;&gt;NancyFX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/bbec75fa-0f31-47e9-a8ce-c301edb2fa4b&#34;&gt;Simple.Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/39ae8dec-d11a-4ac9-974e-be0fdadec71b&#34;&gt;Asp.net MVC5 &amp;amp; Web API2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/24ef5c87-b4e3-4c3b-b126-1064cc66e148&#34;&gt;Fantomas&lt;/a&gt; For code formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/bec977b8-c9d9-4926-999e-e50c4498df8a&#34;&gt;F# Outlining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/f1dae7fe-1ecc-4f1b-86b5-32a2970d012a&#34;&gt;F# web templates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing these template and add on will give you nice ways to start. Trust me I am enjoying far more after these pure &lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharp.org&#34;&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; templates arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people who is new to language, I will start from simple conversation of OOP to Functional programming. Most of them is one to one map only. So, there will be less use of pure functional concept. But slowly will move to more functional style of programming. And trying to achieve nirvana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People trying Scala or coming from Java background &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.playframework.com/&#34;&gt;Play&lt;/a&gt; is choice of framework for you. It is supported by wonderful community and build over the ever powerful &lt;a href=&#34;http://akka.io/&#34;&gt;AKKA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who don&amp;rsquo;t like types or coming from Ruby like language background. You can Clojure for you. And here is twitter conversation with &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodil.org/&#34;&gt;Bodil&lt;/a&gt; for the selection of framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kunjee&#34;&gt;@kunjee&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;m a bit out of touch, used to prefer straight Ring + Compojure, maybe Aleph. But that was before both core.async and Pedestal&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodil Stokke (@bodil) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bodil/statuses/431086156470833152&#34;&gt;February 5, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For People who is going with F# / scala; there are couple of reference reading for getting started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fsharpforfunandprofit.com/&#34;&gt;F# for fun and profit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pluralsight.com/training/Courses/TableOfContents/functional-architecture-fsharp&#34;&gt;Functional Architecture with F#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jessitron.com/&#34;&gt;Jessica Kerr&amp;rsquo;s blog for Scala lovers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do have a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt; : - I am neither expert of &lt;em&gt;web&lt;/em&gt; nor &lt;em&gt;functional programming&lt;/em&gt;. But I know web a little bit more than other programming things and I love functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are we waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kunjan.in/images/rock.gif&#34; alt=&#34;rock&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lets rock.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Diary II</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/archives/java-script-diary-1&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I have written about some &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; basics from the point of view of Software Engineering and Architecture. In this post I will stay close to metal. I will talk about few things we should care about &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; language. Things that’s should be or shouldn’t be in the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am from hard core compile language background. My first company is Game Company where I have built kind of Game Engine and second company I work on C++. Even in third company I was working on web project but most of the time I stay on the server end. So, I have support of managed nature of C Sharp. But in case of &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; it is not true. And many time people makes mistakes what I did. Take &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; as compiled language and work like that only. Obviously its like other programming languages only, its all about if and else but its little bit different. My this post is going to be completed by the video of &lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/&#34;&gt;Channel9&lt;/a&gt; . Here I am attaching video, too. Please go through the video and checkout what should be taken care while writing &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; . Its 50 minutes long and obviously worth spending 50 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;height:544px;width:960px&#34; src=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/MIX/MIX11/OPN08/player?w=960&amp;h=544&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, here is details that are showed in video.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please go through this. Its worth watching and learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Diary I</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long back I have wrote a article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/archives/coffee-with-coffeescript&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; . If anyone see closely its all about writing proper Java Script in easy way. But in many cases its not possible that you got chance to write &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/archives/coffee-with-coffeescript&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; . Or if you are learning some library like &lt;a href=&#34;http://knockoutjs.com/&#34;&gt;KnockoutJS&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://backbonejs.org/&#34;&gt;BackboneJS&lt;/a&gt; , also if you are using some framework like &lt;a href=&#34;http://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt; . Than using &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/archives/coffee-with-coffeescript&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; and also using this function to learn than it will be difficult to catch up together. If you are not powerful enough with one of either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as a base rule. Even you are using &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/archives/coffee-with-coffeescript&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; , you are not escaping from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; . It was there and it will be there for future for sure. So, It is worth learning it. If you have read previous article you must know that I am not that good with &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; . So, I started learning and also thought for note I should put that to a blog. Whatever I learn will document on my blog. So, that will helpful to others and specially for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the guys must be knowing many things. But that’s fine, its again for personal reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is very flexible language. And this allows you to write lovely code without worrying about many things. But again this makes issue many times. And every damn time I will end up messing with that flexibility issue. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-9S0vNlm41AY/URHJtukdwUI/AAAAAAAAArI/blHsaJPrt_c/s800/flexible_4.jpg&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-9S0vNlm41AY/URHJtukdwUI/AAAAAAAAArI/blHsaJPrt_c/s800/flexible_4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;flexible&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And first thing starts with Global variable. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; everything is global by default. So, whenever you are writing any function just like that, they are globally accessible. This is an issue. Just like static variable in any other language. So, don’t write functions just like that. Out anywhere on page. Simple solution of this is self executable anonymous function. That will make everything private. And that’s good at some point at least better than putting everything global. Here everything is private and executed. Just check out the example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(funciton{ 
  var dosomething = function (){ 
  //Here I am doing something 
  } 
})(); 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here do something is completely private. But sometime we need some thing in global. We need to access it from outside. Then there are two patterns for that. Module Pattern and Revealing Module Pattern. I personally prefer Revealing Module Patter. So, I am giving demo for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var REVEALING; 
  REVEALING = ( function () { 
    var dosomething = function (){ 
      //Here I am doing something 
      } 
      var dosomethingmore = function (){ 
      // here I am accessing dosomething 
    function dosomething(); 
    } 
  return 
    {   
    dosomethingmore:dosomethingmore 
    //here only one function is exposed 
    //so it is the only function available outside this namespace 
    } 
})(); 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here one more thing comes in a picture. Namespace, which are not available by default in &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As namespace is not there, we are missing classes too. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is a functional language, it only has functions, also as available as Objects. So, if you like to make things like classes, internally they are functions only. And you also can create constructor based functions too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var Dosomething = ( 
  function (){ 
    function Dosomething(parametername)   
    this.parametername = parametername; 
})(); 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now we have our lovely constructor with parameter. While calling this we can just do like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;var dosomethingobject = new Dosomething( &amp;quot;namehere&amp;quot; );&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after that we can call whatever functions we like to call. It will use the parameter. This is also having same benefit as we are getting with parameterized constructor in structured language. So, this small things always helps to write more readable code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One another things worth nothing here. It is that we can write anything anywhere in &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; does not mean that we should go for that. Even in &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; Single Responsibility Principal should be followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And also parameter name and function name should be self describing. Just because &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is giving freedom we just use it like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many library and other corner cases that can be consider while development client side JavaScript application. But that will be in next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till then happy coding…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee with CoffeeScript</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/coffee-with-coffeescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/coffee-with-coffeescript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in Bangalore, and first thing I found here classically well is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coffee&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously I will not going to talk about coffee here. But about &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; which is as good as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coffee&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; . I come to know about &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/CoffeeScriptSassAndLESSSupportForVisualStudioAndASPNETWithTheMindscapeWebWorkbench.aspx&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; written by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; . And I become addicted to it. I am not much a web guy. I like coding but mostly on server end. And Visual Studio is always there to save me. But when it comes to Java Script, I just crash land any time. I always try to go back to server as soon as possible. Obviously &lt;a href=&#34;http://jquery.com/&#34;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt; is there to bail me out. But still it is only for DOM, but for other things, you have to be expert. Now, here expert means whose written &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; pass the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jslint.com/&#34;&gt;JSLint&lt;/a&gt; with minimum errors. Simple functions and doing some addition is not a big deal but making a library for web application is do a big deal. At least for me. I am so rigid about my code quality and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; is a damn flexible scripting language which easy become a sloppy for me. I always try to follow architecture define by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/JavaScript-Good-Parts-Douglas-Crockford/dp/0596517742?tag=duckduckgo-d-20&#34;&gt;Java Script Good Parts&lt;/a&gt; . But at the end following some rules in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_Sharp_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;C Sharp&lt;/a&gt; is easy than follow in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt;. But God is with me. I found a friend who is damn powerful in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is princess of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; . She write JS like any thing. And standards are not violated at all. I don’t know how someone can write code like that. She is like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cynthiarothrock.org/&#34;&gt;Cynthia Rothrock&lt;/a&gt; of Web. &lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Dw-LumABw0Q/URHJoqyQPlI/AAAAAAAAApY/hnY4qIE8wAE/s800/CR_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, she is like her only. Just like photo. A girl you don’t want to mess with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am not that another person in picture. It just a FYI.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cynthiarothrock.org/&#34;&gt;Cynthia Rothrock&lt;/a&gt; she is also a black belt but in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; . Always kicking around in web arena. Whenever I stuck somewhere she comes laugh at me and solve the problem. And what I am in compare to her, like kid shown here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-TwrCb_2KLk0/URHJyRifiTI/AAAAAAAAAsk/V7mr0dHwQ3o/s800/kids-gi_thumb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A white belt kid. Now what I can do to match the standards with her. Technically I can’t. As she is black belt and I am just a kid. But I am a smart kid. I drink some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cynthiarothrock.org/&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; and write &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; . Yeah, you have black belt and I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cynthiarothrock.org/&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; . Now, I come to point. There is always a need of writing good code, weather it is compiled language or a scripting language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And good code has two main quality as per me. One is its readability and another is extendibility. If I am writing code, other should read it and also able to extend it. Now, if you are writing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; like her, others don’t find any problem to read or extend it but else that will be a problem specifically with scripting languages. It prone to get dirty soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; has major advantage. First thing its readability, and second thing it is just a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; . Here, I am going to use few example from &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; site only. So, if you like to try it out, site have try &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; option, I encouraged you to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;coffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; on local machine there are few options to go with. Today most of the IDE supports add on for &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; . But I prefer the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodejs.org/&#34;&gt;Node&lt;/a&gt; way. Just install it and start firing commands. You can check out home site for &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; to starts with. I am now starting with example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing I love about CoffeeScript is call back function. It wrapper your code around &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; callback function by default. Here is Hello World example of it. I first go with Java Script&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(function () { 
  alert( &amp;quot;this is coffee Script&amp;quot; ); 
}).call( this );
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pretty small things. But I forget many times. This will call anonymous function to self so it will not mess with other libraries around. And what I wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; file. Just one line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alert &amp;quot;this is coffee Script&amp;quot; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. That all I wanted to do. No more function and all that, no more brackets; nothing. Just like any other &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_specific_language&#34;&gt;DSL&lt;/a&gt; , just write what I like to do. It is pretty basic example but even from start, it is showing the power of &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I like is working with arrays. After having list and collection in new languages, working with array is little bit difficult sometime. My friend mention above wrote complete library to get functionality like List in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; . But it is fun to write array in &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally we do things in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; like shown here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(function() {
  var food, foods, _i, _len;

  foods = [&#39;broccoli&#39;, &#39;spinach&#39;, &#39;chocolate&#39;];

  for (_i = 0, _len = foods.length; _i &amp;lt; _len; _i++) {
  food = foods[_i];
  if (food !== &#39;chocolate&#39;) {
      eat(food);
  }
  }

}).call(this); 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;foods = [&#39;broccoli&#39;, &#39;spinach&#39;, &#39;chocolate&#39;]
eat food for food in foods when food isnt &#39;chocolate&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its just pure fun. Here there are few things I like to mentions specifically. First thing I have already mentioned is how to do array thing in fun way. Other thing if you have noticed is a loop with “_” variables. &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; takes care of everything starting from scoping of variable by it self. If you need to mentions at top or take care that it will not go out of scope. That will be taken care, even simple thing like loop is written in way it should be written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example for looping&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; it is like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(function() {
  var countdown, num;

  countdown = (function() {
  var _i, _results;
  _results = [];
  for (num = _i = 10; _i &amp;gt;= 1; num = --_i) {
      _results.push(num);
  }
  return _results;
  })();

}).call(this);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; it is like a one line, giving For Each loop feeling in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;countdown = (num for num in [10..1])&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Here there is one another benefit. If I am insisting for &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; , it is not against the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; but in favor of learning it. One will know the right way of writing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; . As per site of &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; generated by it passed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jslint.com/&#34;&gt;JSLint&lt;/a&gt; without a single error. So, it is good to learn &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if any one is fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; , it supports &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; like syntax in few cases. Obviously web club will like this. You can pass inline variable with “#” and it will work. Let me show you the example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I will go with &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yearsOld = max: 10, ida: 9, tim: 11

ages = for child, age of yearsOld
  &amp;quot;#{child} is #{age}&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; for it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(function() {
  var age, ages, child, yearsOld;

    yearsOld = {
    max: 10,
    ida: 9,
    tim: 11
    };

    ages = (function() {
    var _results;
    _results = [];
    for (child in yearsOld) {
        age = yearsOld[child];
        _results.push(&amp;quot;&amp;quot; + child + &amp;quot; is &amp;quot; + age);
    }
return _results;
  })();

}).call(this);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See it take pretty good care of every damn thing. I just fall in love of this. Pushing everything over the top and returning result, changing things with appropriate variables. Every damn thing. Isn’t it good ???&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few more things for conditional operators and looping. But I like to move on to little bit complex example. If I want to create library like &lt;a href=&#34;http://jquery.com/&#34;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt; , few more things must be there. Now, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t have private , public things or classes by default. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; functions are the classes it self. And there is a trick to do private public thing in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; . Most of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; programmer must have known this. But this thing is fairly easy in &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; . It has its own class syntax and there you go. Code like any other higher level language. Just check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CoffeeScript Code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;class Animal
  constructor: (@name) -&amp;gt;

  move: (meters) -&amp;gt;
  alert @name + &amp;quot; moved #{meters}m.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;class Snake extends Animal
      move: -&amp;gt;
      alert &amp;ldquo;Slithering&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
    super 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;class Horse extends Animal
  move: -&amp;gt;
  alert &amp;quot;Galloping...&amp;quot;
  super 45

sam = new Snake &amp;quot;Sammy the Python&amp;quot;
tom = new Horse &amp;quot;Tommy the Palomino&amp;quot;

sam.move()
tom.move()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is Java Script code (&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(function() {
  var Animal, Horse, Snake, sam, tom,
__hasProp = {}.hasOwnProperty,
__extends = function(child, parent) { for (var key in parent) { if (__hasProp.call(parent, key)) child[key] = parent[key]; } function ctor() { this.constructor = child; } ctor.prototype = parent.prototype; child.prototype = new ctor(); child.__super__ = parent.prototype; return child; };

  Animal = (function() {

  function Animal(name) {
    this.name = name;
  }

  Animal.prototype.move = function(meters) {
    return alert(this.name + (&amp;quot; moved &amp;quot; + meters + &amp;quot;m.&amp;quot;));
  };

  return Animal;

  })();

  Snake = (function(_super) {

__extends(Snake, _super);

function Snake() {
  return Snake.__super__.constructor.apply(this, arguments);
}

Snake.prototype.move = function() {
  alert(&amp;quot;Slithering...&amp;quot;);
  return Snake.__super__.move.call(this, 5);
};

return Snake;

  })(Animal);

  Horse = (function(_super) {

__extends(Horse, _super);

function Horse() {
  return Horse.__super__.constructor.apply(this, arguments);
}

Horse.prototype.move = function() {
  alert(&amp;quot;Galloping...&amp;quot;);
  return Horse.__super__.move.call(this, 45);
};

return Horse;

  })(Animal);

  sam = new Snake(&amp;quot;Sammy the Python&amp;quot;);

  tom = new Horse(&amp;quot;Tommy the Palomino&amp;quot;);

  sam.move();

  tom.move();

}).call(this);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it cool ?? I guess it is. Making library becomes so easy with this kind of syntax. Obviously for the person like me who is from another language background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us see some more complex example. Of function binding. It is easy to bind function. No, extra code at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Account = (customer, cart) -&amp;gt;
  @customer = customer
  @cart = cart

  $(&#39;.shopping_cart&#39;).bind &#39;click&#39;, (event) =&amp;gt;
  @customer.purchase @cart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it will generate appropriate Java Script&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(function() {
  var Account;

  Account = function(customer, cart) {
  var _this = this;
  this.customer = customer;
  this.cart = cart;
  return $(&#39;.shopping_cart&#39;).bind(&#39;click&#39;, function(event) {
    return _this.customer.purchase(_this.cart);
  });
  };

}).call(this);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See. It is fun. If you are thinking that what if you are &lt;a href=&#34;http://jquery.com/&#34;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt; fan like me. Again I like to repeat word from &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; only&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just JavaScript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use any library with &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; . Let’s check out one of the example of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;show_message = (msg) -&amp;gt; 
  $(&#39;#message&#39;).hide().text(msg).fadeIn(2222, -&amp;gt; $(&#39;#message&#39;).append(&#39;!&#39;))

$ -&amp;gt; 
  show_message &amp;quot;world&amp;quot;
  $(&#39;#message&#39;).click -&amp;gt; show_message &amp;quot;you&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here we go with &lt;a href=&#34;http://jquery.com/&#34;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt; code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(function() {
  var show_message;

    show_message = function(msg) {
    return $(&#39;#message&#39;).hide().text(msg).fadeIn(2222, function() {
    return $(&#39;#message&#39;).append(&#39;!&#39;);
  });
  };

  $(function() {
  show_message(&amp;quot;world&amp;quot;);
  return $(&#39;#message&#39;).click(function() {
    return show_message(&amp;quot;you&amp;quot;);
  });
  });

}).call(this);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It becomes more powerful when it joins hands with &lt;a href=&#34;http://jquery.com/&#34;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt; or other libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for whom this is ??? This is for person like me. Or even black belt like my friend. It just fun to write &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; . I don’t insist to use it but I surely insist to give it a try. It is worth investing time in it. Again if you are die hard &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; developer, I don’t think you need this. But again there is no loss in learning new thing. I am just enjoying &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; like anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-x7ptaCkB7bA/URHJvRJbFMI/AAAAAAAAArw/dvsN8HvY0I4/s800/iStock_000005133061XSmall_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here there are clearly two options for most of the developers including me. Either I can have coffee with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt; , doing over time and solving errors. Or I can use &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; and have fun time with my (Black belt) friend. I prefer later one. And trust me this is one the most fun writing article just like &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taste a coffee and have fun. Coding is seriously enjoyable with friends like her and technology like &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; . Special thanks to Jeremy Ashkenas for giving &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffeescript.org/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Coffee!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>