<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Angularjs and the Mess we are in</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know Angularjs?!? Everyone worked is web, mobile, server, windows, mac, Linux, Google, Microsoft or anyway related to this knows about it. And its fun when people tell me
 You know about angularjs. Its pretty hot now a days. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to learn it.
 Oh man&amp;hellip;
Ok I am no expert here in Angularjs. And I prefer not to be expert with any framework. Be it anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typed Hack of Cloudant using F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>There is a continues war between typed and untyped data. But then there is need of finding a middle ground for ever growing application. There is place, a requirement when I feel application should be typed and data store should be untyped. So, I created this little code snippet to access cloudant (a couchbase fork) NOSQL database.
I was knowing about Cloudant from long back. Even before IBM bought it. It is indeed a wonderful service and also kinda free for small stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sails sailing seamlessly on Azure Web Sites</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of frameworks for web development in Nodejs. Many of them are pretty cool. I pretty much like the SailsJS. And also have worked on that in recent past.
Now, when it comes to hosting I love the Azure for various reasons. It is specially awesome when it comes to web sites. You do some experiments and throw it towards azure and that is ready for world to check out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failed attempt to write series, again!</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</guid>
      <description>I have tried writing complete series again. And again failed. And I am stopping it again.
There are couple of reason of it. First and for most thing is I am not good at it. No where near even readable, I guess. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t know reason specifically for that. May be I can write on specific topic better instead of things that are continues.
And that is the reason complete series thing is not that good but individual write ups are getting good reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Servicestack meet F# via Side Waffle</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</guid>
      <description>I have specific love for Servicestack and that is known thing. It is not because it is awesome or the ways it do web service things, no one else is doing. But because of my past with WCF. It is so rocky that I never want to go back. And more over Servicestack doing hell lot of the things under the cover, and that is also without doing any damn thing into XML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.Net MVC5 with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Danial Mohl getting started with Asp.net MVC5 is pretty easy. He had put a tremendous effort to make different kind of templates. Even starting from MVC3 till date now.
Old templates are like there are two projects one is C# and one is F#. C# is having all the Java Script, html, css and stuff while F# is having coding part.
But with time pass and version update, now we are having pure F# templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Functional web</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</guid>
      <description>I am doing web development from quite a long time. And now a days I am keep pushing my self to do functional programming. Learning languages like Haskell, Scala, F#. Obviously I try my hand to other functional languages too as per time permits.
As I am .Net developer my primary focused is working with F# and I will also start from that only. You can also check out other functional articles of mine to check out what I think about functional programming and why it is necessity now a days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Diary II</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-ii/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I have written about some JavaScript basics from the point of view of Software Engineering and Architecture. In this post I will stay close to metal. I will talk about few things we should care about JavaScript language. Things that’s should be or shouldn’t be in the code.
I am from hard core compile language background. My first company is Game Company where I have built kind of Game Engine and second company I work on C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Diary I</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-i/</guid>
      <description>Long back I have wrote a article on CoffeeScript . If anyone see closely its all about writing proper Java Script in easy way. But in many cases its not possible that you got chance to write CoffeeScript . Or if you are learning some library like KnockoutJS or BackboneJS , also if you are using some framework like AngularJS . Than using CoffeeScript and also using this function to learn than it will be difficult to catch up together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee with CoffeeScript</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/coffee-with-coffeescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/coffee-with-coffeescript/</guid>
      <description>I am in Bangalore, and first thing I found here classically well is coffee. Obviously I will not going to talk about coffee here. But about CoffeeScript which is as good as coffee . I come to know about CoffeeScript from the article written by Scott Hanselman . And I become addicted to it. I am not much a web guy. I like coding but mostly on server end. And Visual Studio is always there to save me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>