<rss xmlns:a10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title /><link>http://kunjan.in/rss.xml</link><description /><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-azure-with-fsharp/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-azure-with-fsharp/</link><title>SignalR + Servciestack with F# hosted on Azure</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This may be nastiest thing I have done with deployment after a long time. There is no problem with making it work. But deployment on azure is a serious issue. And &lt;strong&gt;luckily&lt;/strong&gt; I completed that. Yes, there is a luck involved.  &lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-06-23T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This may be nastiest thing I have done with deployment after a long time. There is no problem with making it work. But deployment on azure is a serious issue. And &lt;strong&gt;luckily&lt;/strong&gt; I completed that. Yes, there is a luck involved.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read my previous &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-azure-with-fsharp/"&gt;entry&lt;/a&gt; for running Nancy and SignalR together. Then most of the things are same only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/278caff1-917a-4ac1-a552-e5a2ce0f6e1f"&gt;Servicestack template&lt;/a&gt; to create project. Remove global.asax &amp;amp; global.asax.fs (&lt;em&gt;yes remove it!&lt;/em&gt;). Install SignalR asp.net package from &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/www.nuget.org/packages/Microsoft.AspNet.SignalR/"&gt;nuget&lt;/a&gt;. And copy paste below code in AppCode.fs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;namespace ServicestackSignalRFSharp.App_Start
    open ServiceStack
    open ServiceStack.Common
    open ServicestackSignalRFSharp
    open ServiceStack.Razor
    open System
    open Owin


    type AppHost() = 
        inherit AppHostBase("Hello F# Service", 
                                        typeof&amp;lt;HelloService&amp;gt;.Assembly)
        override this.Configure container =
            Diagnostics.Trace.TraceError("In servicestack configure");
            this.Plugins.Add(new RazorFormat())
            ignore()


        static member start() = 
            let apphost = new AppHost()
            Diagnostics.Trace.TraceError("In servicestack start");
            apphost.Init() |&amp;gt; ignore

    type Startup()=
        member x.Configuration(app : Owin.IAppBuilder) = 
            AppHost.start()
            Diagnostics.Trace.TraceError("In signalr startup");
            app.MapSignalR() |&amp;gt; ignore        


    [&amp;lt;Microsoft.Owin.OwinStartup(typeof&amp;lt;Startup&amp;gt;)&amp;gt;]
    do ()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don't forget to rename the namespace as per your project namespace.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per my Nancy article changed the index.cshtml to get signalR client running. Once done run it. It should work hello world of &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; and Hello Chat from &lt;a href="http://signalr.net"&gt;SignalR&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If things still not work here is my &lt;a href="https://github.com/kunjee17/ServicestackSignalRFSharp/"&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;. Have a look at code. And also it is deployed over &lt;a href="http://servicestacksignalrfsharp.azurewebsites.net/"&gt;azure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;My Personal Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I like to clear it upfront. Even though I was able to run Servicestack and SignalR together but they are still running differently under the hood. Servicestack is hitting asp.net directly and signalR is hitting via &lt;a href="http://owin.org/"&gt;OWIN&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also not making web service real time. It is just both can easily run together. Making them run together was easy task. But deploying on azure is a serious pain in a**. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yes, azure is. It is so damn easy to deploy traditional imperative C# project as azure web site but functional F# project. It is like giving death by a thousand cuts. You solve one issue and another issue came. Just like &lt;em&gt;pipeline&lt;/em&gt; operator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is more like whatever F# is compensating by making development easy, deployment is making it even. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the same with above code. global.asax.fs is working in local, I can even put a break point but it is not working on azure. I put a trace in every possible function and at last find out. (Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/demisbellot"&gt;Demis Bellot&lt;/a&gt; for pointing out this possible issue.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though F# is picking up new height, and I personally contributed and will continue to contribute in templates. But if someone want to take full advantage of F# in web development &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with cloud then s/he need to make one C# project and point F# to them. Just to get best of both worlds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yes, C# is still far better when it comes to csproj file. o_O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual working with functional language is always fun experience and now we have web service that we can scale with real time icing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Servicestack |&gt; Razor |&gt; SignalR |&gt; Azure (with little hiccups) |&gt; F# |&gt; lots of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamanrin3-first-look-mindblown/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamanrin3-first-look-mindblown/</link><title>Xamarin Studio 3 - First Look.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Few days back I got mail from &lt;a href="http://xamarin.com/"&gt;Xamarin&lt;/a&gt; about their launch of new IDE. And also for the registration of webinar. And just like always they again managed to blow my mind. I don't know what else they are having for upcoming &lt;a href="https://evolve.xamarin.com/"&gt;evolve conference.&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-06-01T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Few days back I got mail from &lt;a href="http://xamarin.com/"&gt;Xamarin&lt;/a&gt; about their launch of new IDE. And also for the registration of webinar. And just like always they again managed to blow my mind. I don't know what else they are having for upcoming &lt;a href="https://evolve.xamarin.com/"&gt;evolve conference.&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xamarin is like technical democracy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A company of Technical People, by the technical people and for the technical people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A kinda awesome. Just like their new studio. I am normally work on windows and have Visual Studio installed on my machine. Still many time I prefer to use Xamarin Studio. This new launch will force me more to do so more often. It is not crashing any more like older version while debugging. Even F# is now first class citizen of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am currently facing error while running android + F# project but I guess that will be some issue on my end only.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete new designer, Xamarin.Form api to provide abstraction for LOB applications and flow less studio. If this year will be known as mobile development revolution, Xamarin people will be considered as pioneer of that revolution. I will write more about Mobile application + F#. Now, I can't wait to dirty my hand with some android code and that is also in F#.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3 Xamarin. You know I seriously do love you people.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</link><title>Thanks to wonderful community</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Few days back &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/"&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; tweeted &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a moment, right now, and email the organizers of your favorite Open Source project and THANK THEM.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Scott Hanselman (@shanselman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shanselman/statuses/456216661415034880"&gt;April 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think, I should do that. But twitter is too short and emails boring even I don't have email ids of few of my favourite Open Source project managers. But I am not shying away from thanking. So, I am writing this entry. &lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-04-24T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Few days back &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/"&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; tweeted &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a moment, right now, and email the organizers of your favorite Open Source project and THANK THEM.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Scott Hanselman (@shanselman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shanselman/statuses/456216661415034880"&gt;April 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think, I should do that. But twitter is too short and emails boring even I don't have email ids of few of my favourite Open Source project managers. But I am not shying away from thanking. So, I am writing this entry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Will try to cover as many person as possible who made important part in my life; mainly professionally and sometimes personally too. But if I miss someone, that will be completely unintentional and I am extremely sorry for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a little story. My life was nothing different then every other software engineer. I missed first class by .08% and get out of college in the era of recession. And technically know nothing but little bit of C#.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are pretty normal. Just like every other software person in Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/mu.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All dreams and no way to achieve it. Then luckily or unluckily I move to company where I need to work with &lt;a href="http://www.asp.net/mvc"&gt;Asp.Net MVC&lt;/a&gt;. First thing I did was find something on home site. I don't know there are still any archive available but at that time there is a video series by &lt;a href="http://www.wekeroad.com/"&gt;Rob Conery&lt;/a&gt;. I didn't even know him by then or even his reputation. For me he is Microsoft employee and I am working in Microsoft Technology so he is God sent. Whatever he say is truth nothing but the truth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while wondering around his site, found the video he gave at &lt;a href="http://www.ndcoslo.com/"&gt;NDC conference&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;strong&gt;The Next Big Thing Or Cool-Kid Koolaid? Slicing Through The Rhetoric of MVC vs Web Forms&lt;/strong&gt; . Sorry I didn't found any downloadable link for it but I still do have a copy of it. This video changed me up side down, changed my way of thinking and learning. I started questioning more and learning more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way &lt;strong&gt;Rob&lt;/strong&gt; is responsible for my way to community. Then I became customer/viewer/admirer of &lt;a href="http://tekpub.com/"&gt;tekpub&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Yes, I do earn in rupees and spend in dollars&lt;/em&gt;. but every penny of it is worth it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best thing happen is; it opens the door of open source projects. Its all started with leaving EF and checking out other ORMs. I'll not talk about them now, but will move to my few favourite web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; and other is &lt;a href="http://nancyfx.org/"&gt;NancyFX&lt;/a&gt;. I do like others but this are kinda first ones' I fall in love with. And just like first love nothing can replace that. I like to thank them for their work. Both are wonderful frameworks to do the web development if someone is working in the .Net. One is for rapid web development and other is rapid web service development in true to the nature of Object Oriented Programming. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is one more transaction of me from Object Oriented Programming to Functional Programming. Trust me the F# community is awesome and that is kind of reason behind the transaction. Don't know why but they are simple awesome. And I love to thank them too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am 1986 born, so I am kid to most of the member of the F# community. Most of them are coding even before the day I born. But whenever I stuck somewhere or something they help and give answer to any of my dumbest question. Thank You &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be not knowing philosophical programming without &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jessitron"&gt;Jessica Kerr&lt;/a&gt;, will not be knowing Actors without &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rachelreese"&gt;Rachele Resse&lt;/a&gt;,functional programming will not be fun without &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bodil"&gt;Bodil&lt;/a&gt;'s presentation/talks, without infinite force of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dsyme"&gt;Don Syme&lt;/a&gt; there is no me &amp;lt;3 F# and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ptrelford"&gt;Phillip Trelford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/7sharp9"&gt;Dave Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ScottWlaschin"&gt;Scott Wlaschin&lt;/a&gt; and others who are always there for community. I never meet any of them but they are always there whenever I need them. May be this is the reason Internet was invented, or if I say specifically then social network invented. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry if I missed any other community members. But there is a long list. Hopefully someday I meet them and thank them in personally.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even this blog is running on &lt;a href="https://github.com/Sandra/Sandra.Snow"&gt;Snow&lt;/a&gt; made by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/philliphaydon"&gt;Phillip Haydon&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks &amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-azure-with-fsharp/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-azure-with-fsharp/</link><title>SignalR + Nancy with F# hosted on Azure</title><description>&lt;p&gt;What you feel if you meet your favourite actor? Feeling is wonderful right? Now, add the your actress in the mixture. Have you said WOW??? How about director? Still heart is beating?!? How about having dinner with them? Nothing can be better than that.
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-03-27T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What you feel if you meet your favourite actor? Feeling is wonderful right? Now, add the your actress in the mixture. Have you said WOW??? How about director? Still heart is beating?!? How about having dinner with them? Nothing can be better than that.
&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;
I am having kinda same feeling. It is nothing new that &lt;a href="http://nancyfx.org/"&gt;Nancy&lt;/a&gt; is dancing quite comfortable with &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;. And thanks to Daniel Mohl we are also having &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/b55b8aac-b11a-4a6a-8a77-2153f46f4e2f"&gt;templates&lt;/a&gt; to get started with Nancy and F#. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I was doing some experiments around it. It was quite good. But how about running it on Owin. hmmm, it works flow less. Nothing more on code side other than few lines here and there. Then I found few projects running &lt;a href="http://signalr.net/"&gt;SignalR&lt;/a&gt; with F#. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knowing Nancy from a long time. But SignalR, I don't know anything about it. The only thing I know is that, it is super awesome. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first task is to run Nancy on Owin. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are simple steps. Using template create a asp.net host with razor project. remove asp.net host and add &lt;a href="http://www.nuget.org/packages/Nancy.Owin/"&gt;Owin host&lt;/a&gt; using nuget package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need to add startup file. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type Startup() = 
    member x.Configuration(app : Owin.IAppBuilder) =  app.UseNancy() |&amp;gt; ignore


[&amp;lt;Microsoft.Owin.OwinStartup(typeof&amp;lt;Startup&amp;gt;)&amp;gt;]
do ()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And add simple Nancy code. The regular one. Nothing fancy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is bootstrap class&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type Bootstrapper() =
    inherit DefaultNancyBootstrapper()
    override x.ApplicationStartup(container:TinyIoCContainer, pipelines:IPipelines) = 
        StaticConfiguration.DisableErrorTraces &amp;lt;- false
        base.ApplicationStartup(container,pipelines)
        ignore()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this is needed to trace the error if anything is there at nancy end.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And our index module &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type IndexModule() as x =
    inherit NancyModule()
    do x.Get.["/"] &amp;lt;- fun _ -&amp;gt; box x.View.["Index"]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty lame right. But it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, add &lt;a href="http://www.nuget.org/packages/Microsoft.AspNet.SignalR/"&gt;Signalr asp.net host nuget package&lt;/a&gt; to project. As startup file is already there; no need to create one more. Just minor modification will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type Startup() = 
    member x.Configuration(app : Owin.IAppBuilder) =  app.MapSignalR().UseNancy() |&amp;gt; ignore
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That MapSignalR thing is additionally added. I have just followed Hello World example of real time world. Create a chat application. So, here is the hub to broadcast the message to all users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type ChatHub() as this = 
    inherit Hub()
    member x.send (name : string, msg : string) = this.Clients.All?broadcastMessage (name, msg) |&amp;gt; ignore
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, copy paste code for html part. Here is code snippet. There is no need to go into detail as of now for JavaScript part.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Here is singnal R working great with Nancy&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div class="container"&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;input type="text" id="message" /&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;input type="button" id="sendmessage" value="Send" /&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;input type="hidden" id="displayname" /&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ul id="discussion"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!--Script references. --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!--Reference the jQuery library. --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script src="Scripts/jquery-1.6.4.min.js"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!--Reference the SignalR library. --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script src="Scripts/jquery.signalR-2.0.2.min.js"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!--Reference the autogenerated SignalR hub script. --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script src="signalr/hubs"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!--Add script to update the page and send messages.--&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;
    $(function () {
        // Declare a proxy to reference the hub.
        var chat = $.connection.chatHub;
        // Create a function that the hub can call to broadcast messages.
        chat.client.broadcastMessage = function (name, msg) {
            // Html encode display name and message.

            var encodedName = $('&amp;lt;div /&amp;gt;').text(name).html();
            var encodedMsg = $('&amp;lt;div /&amp;gt;').text(msg).html();
            // Add the message to the page.
            $('#discussion').append('&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;' + encodedName
                + '&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;:&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;' + encodedMsg + '&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;');
        };
        // Get the user name and store it to prepend to messages.
        $('#displayname').val(prompt('Enter your name:', ''));
        // Set initial focus to message input box.
        $('#message').focus();
        // Start the connection.
        $.connection.hub.start().done(function () {
            $('#sendmessage').click(function () {
                // Call the Send method on the hub.
                chat.server.send($('#displayname').val(), $('#message').val());
                // Clear text box and reset focus for next comment.
                $('#message').val('').focus();
            });
        });
    });
&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, there is one "?" thing before broadcastMessage function. That is where dynamic method is getting called. F# do not support dynamic by default but there are many work around available. I personally prefer &lt;a href="http://www.nuget.org/packages/FSharp.Dynamic/"&gt;Fsharp.dynamic&lt;/a&gt; library. It is better than other code snippets I found over other sites. But that is all personal choice how one like to handle dynamic functions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it is done. Hit F5 and you are ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is fun of working with Web if I can't publish it. But for now with F# web templates it is not possible. And that is known &lt;a href="https://github.com/fsharp/FSharpCommunityTemplates/issues/28"&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;. So, if I like to publish it on cloud like azure I need to give git hooks. That is easiest thing I can think off. But road is still not that smooth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deployment will break with some weird error. I followed &lt;a href="http://blog.ploeh.dk/2013/08/26/running-a-pure-f-web-api-on-azure-web-sites/"&gt;Mark's article&lt;/a&gt; to make it work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needed to add below lines to .fsproj file after its own import tags. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Import Project="$(VSToolsPath)\WebApplications\Microsoft.WebApplication.targets" 
        Condition="'$(VSToolsPath)' != ''" /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;Import Project="$(MSBuildExtensionsPath32)\Microsoft\VisualStudio\v11.0\WebApplications\Microsoft.WebApplication.targets" 
        Condition="true" /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And things are working like anything. No, issues at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nancy |&gt; Razor |&gt; SignalR |&gt; Azure |&gt; F# |&gt; lots of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please give it a shot. If it break somewhere let me know will try to solve it. Any suggestion to make things even better and streamlined are always welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; Here is my &lt;a href="https://github.com/kunjee17/NancySignalRFSharp"&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt; with updated code. Project created with web express 2013. Also it is deployed over &lt;a href="http://nancysignalrfsharp.azurewebsites.net/"&gt;azure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</link><title>Why I moved away from Sencha to Phonejs?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://sencha.com"&gt;Sencha&lt;/a&gt; is well known framework for mobile development. Not only mobile development but it is doing a hell of a lot of thing other than mobile development. Not only that it is surely having wonderful history with &lt;a href="https://www.sencha.com/products/extjs/"&gt;JavaScript framework development&lt;/a&gt;. I don't have anything to complain against that. 
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-03-24T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://sencha.com"&gt;Sencha&lt;/a&gt; is well known framework for mobile development. Not only mobile development but it is doing a hell of a lot of thing other than mobile development. Not only that it is surely having wonderful history with &lt;a href="https://www.sencha.com/products/extjs/"&gt;JavaScript framework development&lt;/a&gt;. I don't have anything to complain against that. 
&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;
But today I am going to talk about specifically one framework, that is &lt;a href="https://www.sencha.com/products/touch/"&gt;Sencha Touch&lt;/a&gt;. I was trying to something that can developed once and deployed everywhere. &lt;em&gt;Yes, it is kinda new trend in mobile development now a days.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I do have working experience with &lt;a href="http://jquerymobile.com/"&gt;JQuery Moblie&lt;/a&gt;, but still I choose Sencha, due to its performance and preference for architecture. I did same mistake which &lt;a href="http://datachomp.com/"&gt;Rob Sullivan&lt;/a&gt; mentioned couple of days back. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kunjee"&gt;@kunjee&lt;/a&gt; it’s always a balance of being able to push yourself but make sure you don’t go over a cliff from the push.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rob Sullivan (@DataChomp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DataChomp/statuses/447559429353787392"&gt;March 23, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I practically pushed my self over the cliff. I am particularly having nothing against &lt;a href="https://www.sencha.com/products/touch/"&gt;Sencha Touch&lt;/a&gt;. It is nothing but the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;overly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; awesome product. May be problem is on my side. I am not &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; doing mobile work. Mobile application is part of bigger idea or bigger application. So, there are many other things than running that very same thing on mobile. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Framework should help and if I can't get it up and running in hours it is coming into my way of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That same thing happened with me. I have tried &lt;a href="https://www.sencha.com/products/touch/"&gt;Sencha Touch&lt;/a&gt;, other than having lots of boiler plate code; Sencha command tool is also broken. That is also few months back there is no way to generate store using command. I never understand why? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of programming which is ruling the market as of now. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming"&gt;Object Oriented Programming&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming"&gt;Functional Programming&lt;/a&gt;. In latter one you can compose functions and normally code tends to stay small while is first one code is more so there is complete tooling chain around that. One of that is &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scaffolding"&gt;Scaffolding&lt;/a&gt;. If that is broken, there is no way I can write that much code and that also in JavaScript. Dynamic typing language is good if I can use that nature, if I am writing code like static typing that is like worst of both world.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is already functionally object oriented language. If I am doing only object oriented part of it I need my tools up and running perfectly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also tried &lt;a href="https://www.sencha.com/products/architect/"&gt;Sencha Architect&lt;/a&gt;. It is good for starting but after using for sometime, it started coming into my way. And I was spending more time in learning tool than solving the real problem. I personally don't like this kinda tools. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May be I am not smart enough to use &lt;a href="http://www.sencha.com"&gt;Sencha&lt;/a&gt; products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[UPDATE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend quite a amount of time learning Sencha, and same amount of time I was able complete application using more simpler &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/phonejs.devexpress.com"&gt;Phonejs&lt;/a&gt;. It is little slow at start up but at least I am not slowing down my application to get out of development state. &lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attemp-to-write-series/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attemp-to-write-series/</link><title>Failed attempt to write series, again!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have tried writing complete series again. And again failed. And I am stopping it again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are couple of reason of it. First and for most thing is I am not good at it. No where near even readable, I guess. Now, I don't know reason specifically for that. May be I can write on specific topic better instead of things that are continues. 
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-03-23T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have tried writing complete series again. And again failed. And I am stopping it again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are couple of reason of it. First and for most thing is I am not good at it. No where near even readable, I guess. Now, I don't know reason specifically for that. May be I can write on specific topic better instead of things that are continues. 
&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;
And that is the reason complete series thing is not that good but individual write ups are getting good reviews. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one more things. Few things are just very random that can't fit in series at all. Few days back I was trying to run SignalR with F#. I succeeded but that will not fit here. Before that there was article about &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/"&gt;getting started with Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; from very zero. And that also can't fit here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I finally though to kill it for while. Because of this I couldn't able to write few other things I like to write. I am putting this in this series as completely non-technical part. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be more articles about web, game and F# but not in series form. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, wait for next one. &lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</link><title>Servicestack F# template. Starting from the Start.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have already wrote a blog &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-circle-is-complete/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about how to get started with service stack if any one is using templates. It is pretty easy. Just install and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Service Stack&lt;/a&gt; is moved to V4 with some breaking changes. I had give details about updating it. But still it is little bit more complicated or confusing if I can say.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-02-13T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have already wrote a blog &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-circle-is-complete/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about how to get started with service stack if any one is using templates. It is pretty easy. Just install and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Service Stack&lt;/a&gt; is moved to V4 with some breaking changes. I had give details about updating it. But still it is little bit more complicated or confusing if I can say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kunjee"&gt;@kunjee&lt;/a&gt; Sure, otherwise a tutorial on getting SS v4 + F# together without templates would be better than starting from a broken v3 one.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Demis Bellot (@demisbellot) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/demisbellot/statuses/433545493738582016"&gt;February 12, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is the conversation inspired me to write this blog. And also it will be fun to write back stories. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if any one want to get started with SS without templates. They need to download template of &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/b55b8aac-b11a-4a6a-8a77-2153f46f4e2f"&gt;Nancy&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, the cousin sibling of SS and other best thing happen to web part of  .Net after .Net it self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create new project and select Empty ASP.Net option. And remove all other packages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;we are doing this just to save our self from using complicated project GUIDs. If any one wanted to go raw, s/he need to select library project in F# and set GUID so it will be web application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now install, SS from nuget. Preferably with Asp.Net host. Use this &lt;code&gt;Install-Package servicestack.Host.AspNet&lt;/code&gt; . If any one prefer not search nuget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, delete every file with .cs extension. &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;, we are doing it in &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, delete default.htm and *.js files. But keep the App_Start folder. We may need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is almost done. Now, create AppHost.fs in App_start folder. Write a namespace you like and copy paste below code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type AppHost() = 
    inherit AppHostBase("Hello F# Service", typeof&amp;lt;HelloService&amp;gt;.Assembly)
    override this.Configure container = ignore()
    static member start() = 
        let apphost = new AppHost()
        apphost.Init() |&amp;gt; ignore
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, create HelloService.fs outside somewhere. and copy paste below code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[&amp;lt;CLIMutable&amp;gt;]
    type HelloResponse = 
        { Result : string }


    [&amp;lt;Route("/hello")&amp;gt;]
    [&amp;lt;Route("/hello/{name}")&amp;gt;]
    type Hello() = 
        interface IReturn&amp;lt;HelloResponse&amp;gt;
        member val Name = "" with get, set


    type HelloService() = 
        inherit Service()
        member this.Any(request : Hello) = { Result = "Hello " + request.Name }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, final settings. Add global.asax.fs file. And copy - paste below code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type Global() = 
    inherit System.Web.HttpApplication()

    member x.Application_Start (sender:Object, e:EventArgs) = 
        App_Start.AppHost.start() 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need to add global.asax file too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add this line to it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;%@ Application Inherits="ServicestackAspNetHost.Global" %&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do check for namespace name. This my project's namespace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you may get error that couple of system references are missing. Please add them. I got for System.data and also for System.xml.linq&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;F# visual studio project is poor with compilation sequence. So, do keep open project file in your favorite text editor. If there is some error like "xyxy" is not defined. Most of the time it is compilation sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything builds. It is out first victory. Run it. It should show, metadata page of SS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is done for people just wanted to create back end for their single page application or mobile application or thick client. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For complete web story lets add razor engine to it. Fire &lt;code&gt;Install-Package ServiceStack.Razor&lt;/code&gt; in package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add Default.cshtml file. Add some html text to test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, here is complicated part. We can't add folder in F# projects. But as it is Asp.Net web project too, we can add Asp.Net project folder. Add one of the folder and rename it to &lt;em&gt;Views&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add two files. One is _Layout.cshtml and other is Hello.cshtml. Don't forget to set compile type content for all cshtml files. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is content for _Layout.cshtml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang="en-us"&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;@ViewBag.Title&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;style type="text/css"&amp;gt;
        body {
            background: #E6E6E6;
        }
    &amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
    @RenderBody()

    &amp;lt;h6 style="font-size:12px; color: #999; position: fixed; bottom: -25px; right: 10px;"&amp;gt;
        @Env.ServerUserAgent
    &amp;lt;/h6&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is content for Hello.cshtml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@using ServiceStackAspNetHost
@inherits ViewPage&amp;lt;HelloResponse&amp;gt; 
@{
    Layout = "_Layout";
    ViewBag.Title = "Hello Page";
}

&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;
    Hello Page
    &amp;lt;a href="/hello"&amp;gt;Default Hello&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;a href="/hello/fsharp"&amp;gt;Hello With get Request&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;


    &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Model binding with DTO Response&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;@Model.Result&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much same as we do in C# projects. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are almost done. Now we need to tell AppHost to add razor plugin. Change code as below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;override this.Configure container =
            this.Plugins.Add(new RazorFormat())
            ignore()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, rebuild and run it. It will show default page on "/" location and Hello page on "/Hello" location. Even you can access metadata page too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that tough I guess. A little bit more code then normal one but as in F# it will be same as normal code in C#. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I love SS that is true thing, but I love Nancy too. Will not lie on &lt;strong&gt;Valentine's Day&lt;/strong&gt;. Just to clarify as I used Nancy template to work with SS. If I have to do some web application work Nancy is weapon of choice and for API like thing SS is always there. People who created both are damn smart and more importantly friendly one. In .Net where OSS and OSS community story is not that good, these people are making the difference. Obviously I can't forget to mention F# community, they are awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-circle-is-complete/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-circle-is-complete/</link><title>Servicestack F# template Update. Circle is Complete.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Few day's back I wrote a &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-sidewaffle/"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about how I created &lt;a href="http://sidewaffle.com/"&gt;side waffle&lt;/a&gt; templates for &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href="http://blog.danielmohl.com/"&gt;Daniel Mohl&lt;/a&gt;, merged the pull request. Add the missing bits make it working and it is up on &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/278caff1-917a-4ac1-a552-e5a2ce0f6e1f"&gt;visual studio gallery&lt;/a&gt;. I seriously like to thank Daniel for this work and support even after his own hectic schedule of day job. And a wonderful members of &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; community. 
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-02-11T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Few day's back I wrote a &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-sidewaffle/"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about how I created &lt;a href="http://sidewaffle.com/"&gt;side waffle&lt;/a&gt; templates for &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href="http://blog.danielmohl.com/"&gt;Daniel Mohl&lt;/a&gt;, merged the pull request. Add the missing bits make it working and it is up on &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/278caff1-917a-4ac1-a552-e5a2ce0f6e1f"&gt;visual studio gallery&lt;/a&gt;. I seriously like to thank Daniel for this work and support even after his own hectic schedule of day job. And a wonderful members of &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; community. 
&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;
Here, I am sharing few details of the template, I have created. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four templates available now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servicestack with Asp.Net host&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servicestack with Asp.Net host and Razor Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servicestack with Self host&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servicestack with Self host and Razor Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was working on Asp.Net MVC with Servicestack but then work in still progress. As, most of the people who are using servicestack can go with above options as Razor view engine now available. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just try out all options and pick which suits for specific need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, all templates are using &lt;strong&gt;3.71&lt;/strong&gt; version of SS. As, it is the last version under MIT license. Why I am using that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;oh dear, adding task to remove servicestack from solution &lt;a href="https://t.co/STpdEKQiJC"&gt;https://t.co/STpdEKQiJC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Simon Cousins (@simontcousins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simontcousins/statuses/408182117579776000"&gt;December 4, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who are starting, or just like to stay with older version till the product kick off. They can continue with &lt;strong&gt;3.71&lt;/strong&gt;.  And else it is a wonderful solution, that is worth &lt;a href="https://servicestack.net/pricing"&gt;buying&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do take care while fire up command of update-package without thinking a bit. If there is a need of using old version &lt;strong&gt;PLEASE&lt;/strong&gt; don't update it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if someone like to update from 3.71 to 4.X. There are couple of breaking changes there. Here are the steps to make it work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the template from the &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/278caff1-917a-4ac1-a552-e5a2ce0f6e1f"&gt;Visual Studio gallery&lt;/a&gt; and install it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yes, it will also work with latest express version too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create new project and choose any template. Select OK. It is done. Easy enough right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press F5, and it will work with "Hello World" code. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Code may seems little dirty. It misses comments and also read me. It will be there in future updates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But current code is so less that it will be not that problematic to understand it. Obviously if you know &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt; a little bit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Things needed to update the version&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire a update command from nuget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are chances that one need to fire it more than one time, check package.config that all versions are updated to same version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove all the *.cs files and unwanted .htm, .js, .css files for now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now there will be some errors about namespace, remove unwanted namespace as code is merged to base namespace for many files
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove ServiceStack.ServiceInterface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove ServiceStack.ServiceHost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove ServiceStack.WebHost.Endpoints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebuild it and run it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we get error about Razor pages, remove 1.0.0.0 version line from web config if there is 2.0.0.0 one is already there else change 1.0.0.0 to 2.0.0.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebuild and run it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now if there is a error "Object reference not set to an instance of an object." then we are on right track. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In AppHost.fs file replace &lt;code&gt;apphost.Init()&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;apphost.Init() |&amp;gt; ignore&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;This is breaking change for V4&lt;/strong&gt; please do not forget this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, we need out namespace so, remove "ServiceStackAspNetHost" with your desired project namespace in entire project including web.config file. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove any multiple entries of namespace from namespace section in web.cofig file. Do keep one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebuild and run it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should work. If still you stuck any where? I am also putting all V4 projects too, over my &lt;a href="https://github.com/kunjee17/ServiceStackFSharp/tree/master/V4"&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;, have a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also started complete series called &lt;a href="http://kunjan.in/category/functional-web/"&gt;Functional Web&lt;/a&gt;, where I will be putting everything I know to get started. Not only for SS but also for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as everyone is putting up API for their web application. Why we should stay behind?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback and comments are always welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-sidewaffle/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-sidewaffle/</link><title>When Servicestack meet F# via Side Waffle</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have specific love for &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; and that is known thing. It is not because it is awesome or the ways it do web service things, no one else is doing. But because of my past with WCF. It is so rocky that I never want to go back.  And more over &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; doing hell lot of the things under the cover, and that is also without doing any damn thing into &lt;strong&gt;XML&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hell, yes.. No XML... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I can write on and on for &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; but for now it is not the topic. Topic is about &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/YakShavingDefinedIllGetThatDoneAsSoonAsIShaveThisYak.aspx"&gt;Shaving the Yak&lt;/a&gt;. There are many hatters of Visual Studio and its project file. I also don't mind sometimes joining the league. But for most of the cases it is doing many things, that we need to do otherwise.
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-02-06T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have specific love for &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; and that is known thing. It is not because it is awesome or the ways it do web service things, no one else is doing. But because of my past with WCF. It is so rocky that I never want to go back.  And more over &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; doing hell lot of the things under the cover, and that is also without doing any damn thing into &lt;strong&gt;XML&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hell, yes.. No XML... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I can write on and on for &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; but for now it is not the topic. Topic is about &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/YakShavingDefinedIllGetThatDoneAsSoonAsIShaveThisYak.aspx"&gt;Shaving the Yak&lt;/a&gt;. There are many hatters of Visual Studio and its project file. I also don't mind sometimes joining the league. But for most of the cases it is doing many things, that we need to do otherwise.
&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;
And I am saying this because I have done this while creating templates for  &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt;. My first experience is damn flow less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created one sample application and &lt;a href="http://blog.danielmohl.com/"&gt;Daniel Mohl&lt;/a&gt; did the mojo jojo part. And template is up and running. But after that he was little bit busy with day job so I got that task. And first challenge was to run &lt;a href="http://servicestack.net/"&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; with F#. Console application is pretty easy as I have done it &lt;a href="https://github.com/kunjee17/ServiceStackHeroku"&gt;earlier too&lt;/a&gt; and deployed it to &lt;a href="http://servicestackheroku.herokuapp.com/"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;. But with Asp.Net it was giving weird issue. After struggling for two weeks and asking community over twitter, I got answer from &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/21213363/servicestack-razor-page-is-getting-added-to-content"&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;. Damn silly mistake. I copy pasted code from self host and that is spinning up two server. Once solved I was so happy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But next thing is waiting for me is to make is template. I was having no idea how to do that. Other than I was having link where to give pull request. At this point &lt;a href="http://sidewaffle.com/"&gt;Side Waffle&lt;/a&gt; came to rescue. Just a 5 minutes video and you are done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I do got some hiccups, like I was unable to created project at first. But then I did &lt;em&gt;hacking&lt;/em&gt; , lamest one. Did copy paste of other working project, removed their data and insert mine. And it was working.  Obviously this was not the best way but for now it is working. And I am the happy one for now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I have given my first pull request to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;F# Community&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; project. Yes, Yes, Yes... It is time for celebration. This can not be possible without a wonderful helping community over github, twitter, stackoverflow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But two things are certain from my experience that Yak Shaving is pain in a##, and &lt;a href="http://sidewaffle.com/"&gt;Side Waffle&lt;/a&gt; is flow less in saving it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will highly encourage people having .Net Open Source project, please do make template and provide the boiler plate code. It will be hell easy to get started in that way. And it will save time from doing initial set up to get up and started. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;  Currently I am putting together V4 templates at my &lt;a href="https://github.com/kunjee17/ServiceStackFSharp"&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;.  And again facing issue to make Asp.Net version running. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am waiting for my pull request to get accepted. Once done, do have a look. You will see that F# and Servicestack are made for each other. Both are strongly typed, believed in message driven design and async model of working. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In current state where everyone is making API, this is most &lt;em&gt;viable&lt;/em&gt; option for .Net people to have. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Template is currently having V3.71, it is still under MIT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if someone like to move to V4, that is also not that costly option for the worth Servicestack bringing to development. Once I ll get up and running V4, I will put the template of that too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Community members, if there are any suggestion, comments please do provide. And obviously I am happy to take pull request for my template projects too. Different combinations of Servicestack option will be great. Also, if someone can check out issue that will be also great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update2:&lt;/strong&gt;  Latest template is up at &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/278caff1-917a-4ac1-a552-e5a2ce0f6e1f"&gt;Visual Studio Gallery&lt;/a&gt;, now having asp.net host too. There are three additional templates. And also V4 issue is solved and project is working now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks F#, Servicestack and specially Side Waffle. &lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://kunjan.in/2014/02/aspnet-mvc/</guid><link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/aspnet-mvc/</link><title>Asp.Net MVC5 with F#</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://blog.danielmohl.com/"&gt;Danial Mohl&lt;/a&gt; getting started with Asp.net MVC5 is pretty easy. He had put a tremendous effort to make different kind of templates. Even starting from MVC3 till date now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old templates are like there are two projects one is C# and one is &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;. C# is having all the &lt;a href="http://vanilla-js.com/"&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt;, html, css and stuff while F# is having coding part. 
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-02-05T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://blog.danielmohl.com/"&gt;Danial Mohl&lt;/a&gt; getting started with Asp.net MVC5 is pretty easy. He had put a tremendous effort to make different kind of templates. Even starting from MVC3 till date now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old templates are like there are two projects one is C# and one is &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;F#&lt;/a&gt;. C# is having all the &lt;a href="http://vanilla-js.com/"&gt;Java Script&lt;/a&gt;, html, css and stuff while F# is having coding part. 
&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;
But with time pass and version update, now we are having pure F# templates. A single project of F# having code, Java Script, cshtml, html, CSS everything. It is far more fun and easy to get started with. At the end of day F# is all about compressing code. Doing more with less code. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scala people, play is almost same as MVC framework. If you are following, code will be almost same only. I will still try to put code snippets wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you haven't downloaded template yet. Please check out my previous post the first one in series and download template. Once installed you are up and running to write some MVC code. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am assuming that people trying this; is quite familiar with MVC and other concepts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I will be doing one to one map between C# and F# code. Just to get familiar with syntax. Then will move to optimized code to make it more functional. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note&lt;/strong&gt; If you are not having Visual Studio Pro or higher one. Do not worry, templates are working with Express versions also. As per latest release F# is now primarily supported by &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org/use/windows/"&gt;Desktop and Web Express version&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install template, create new project with MVC5 and Web API option. Hit F5 and it is done. You are up and running. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling great?!? It is just started. 
&lt;img src="http://kunjan.in/images/rollercoasterride.gif" alt="roller coaster ride" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item></channel></rss>