<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Business</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/back-to-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/back-to-business/</guid>
      <description>It have been long that I was doing active blogging. There are multiple reason for that, and on of them is being a lazy ass.
I changed my blog from Orchard to Docpad for almost no reason. I just wanted my few page look different then other pages. And that will little bit more effort if I am going to do it with Orchard. So, I check out on net how to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Never Changed!!! Guiding Principles to Software Development</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/11/something-never-changed-guiding-principals-to-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/11/something-never-changed-guiding-principals-to-software-development/</guid>
      <description>I am particularly a lazy guy. I don’t work hard, stay back and never show sad face to issue or bug. Obviously many don’t like me for this. But again “who cares?”. But one thing is sure for me, I always ready to learn new things and obviously always work for better code. At the end of day it is just a code, bugs will be there and me too , to solve the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DI of FDI (Foreign direct investment)</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/di-of-fdi-foreign-direct-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/di-of-fdi-foreign-direct-investment/</guid>
      <description>It has been a week or so, every day news paper and news channel are full with news of FDI in India . Even Facebook is not taking a step back and speak in favor of both side. FDI in retails should be allowed or not.
I am not a politician, so as engineer I will do data analysis of FDI in India. now, for the sake of example we consider that FDI is allowed in retail market (PS : I personally think that it is going to be allowed) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot of Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/snapshot-of-steve-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/snapshot-of-steve-jobs/</guid>
      <description>I was reading article on Wall Street Journal , about Steve Jobs. It was wonderful article taken by Ralph, at time of starting phase of apple.
It was the time of change, if any one is familiar with the history of&amp;nbsp; computer world, must know the era of changing. When companies like Microsoft and Apple started and change the rule of game. They change the way of thinking that computer should be big and for co-operate work only.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>