<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functional Web on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/functional-web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Functional Web on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/functional-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated Fable - Architecture &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2018/03/opinionated-fable-architecture-and-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2018/03/opinionated-fable-architecture-and-performance/</guid>
      <description>There can&amp;rsquo;t be better time for writing this blog. As Fable 2.0 is on the horizon it would be good to see what 1.0 already can do. And I can also wish few things to be added to 2.0.
I have chosen Fable after evaluating couple of options like TypeScript-React-Redux, Elm, Aurelia, Angular. One thing I was pretty much sure that I wanted static typing in my project. Because I did have first hand experience with big fat Angular application built using JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Chaat with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Here is my Birthday blog post, as a part of FSAdvent - 2017. Just like previous two years, I hope you will enjoy this one too. Comments and corrections are very much welcomed.
 Why Chaat? and What is Chaat? If anyone wanted to show real time application, then Chat is kind of to-do list of that type of applications. Now Functional Chat is a very limited title and can&amp;rsquo;t show all the things I wanted to show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Services with Servicestack and F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/reactive-services-with-servicestack-and-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/reactive-services-with-servicestack-and-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Reactive word is not new nowadays. If you want your library to get limelight, use reactive word in the name any way possible and it will definitely get initial attention. Reactive word is appropriate for things that follows reactive manifesto. That is true for now. And there are many variant of libraries on server and client to fulfil this.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the start of web.
We were having old web were we used to do post event of page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typed Hack of Cloudant using F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>There is a continues war between typed and untyped data. But then there is need of finding a middle ground for ever growing application. There is place, a requirement when I feel application should be typed and data store should be untyped. So, I created this little code snippet to access cloudant (a couchbase fork) NOSQL database.
I was knowing about Cloudant from long back. Even before IBM bought it. It is indeed a wonderful service and also kinda free for small stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web programming and F# still a Far Cry?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</guid>
      <description>F# is wonderful language. And luckily or unluckily I do Web Programming (now a days mostly that). So, it is always a preference to use it, wherever possible. But even in 2014 end it is still pain in a**.
I did make templates for Servicestack and I will continue to support that. But when it comes to real projects they go far beyond templates.
I recently experimenting on something and obviously I am gonna use templates created by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My broken marriage with C# and extramarital affair with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>*NOTE- As per today I am neither married nor committed. And for that case never married and never committed. :P*
 Whoever is following my progress must be knowing my love for F#. Neither me nor F# knows exact time and date when that happen. But now it is like if few days I have to pass without writing few lines to(in) F# then it felt like I have left software engineering for good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Servciestack with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>This may be nastiest thing I have done with deployment after a long time. There is no problem with making it work. But deployment on azure is a serious issue. And luckily I completed that. Yes, there is a luck involved.
If you read my previous entry for running Nancy and SignalR together. Then most of the things are same only.
Use Servicestack template to create project. Remove global.asax &amp;amp; global.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Nancy with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>What you feel if you meet your favourite actor? Feeling is wonderful right? Now, add the your actress in the mixture. Have you said WOW??? How about director? Still heart is beating?!? How about having dinner with them? Nothing can be better than that.
I am having kinda same feeling. It is nothing new that Nancy is dancing quite comfortable with F#. And thanks to Daniel Mohl we are also having templates to get started with Nancy and F#.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failed attempt to write series, again!</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</guid>
      <description>I have tried writing complete series again. And again failed. And I am stopping it again.
There are couple of reason of it. First and for most thing is I am not good at it. No where near even readable, I guess. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t know reason specifically for that. May be I can write on specific topic better instead of things that are continues.
And that is the reason complete series thing is not that good but individual write ups are getting good reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Servicestack meet F# via Side Waffle</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</guid>
      <description>I have specific love for Servicestack and that is known thing. It is not because it is awesome or the ways it do web service things, no one else is doing. But because of my past with WCF. It is so rocky that I never want to go back. And more over Servicestack doing hell lot of the things under the cover, and that is also without doing any damn thing into XML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.Net MVC5 with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Danial Mohl getting started with Asp.net MVC5 is pretty easy. He had put a tremendous effort to make different kind of templates. Even starting from MVC3 till date now.
Old templates are like there are two projects one is C# and one is F#. C# is having all the Java Script, html, css and stuff while F# is having coding part.
But with time pass and version update, now we are having pure F# templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Functional web</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</guid>
      <description>I am doing web development from quite a long time. And now a days I am keep pushing my self to do functional programming. Learning languages like Haskell, Scala, F#. Obviously I try my hand to other functional languages too as per time permits.
As I am .Net developer my primary focused is working with F# and I will also start from that only. You can also check out other functional articles of mine to check out what I think about functional programming and why it is necessity now a days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>