<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/tekpub/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/tekpub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Open letter to Tekpub</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/open-letter-to-tekpub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/open-letter-to-tekpub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not much a writer kind of person. If you drop a math puzzle, probably I will do it in better way. But sometimes it is necessity to do thing even though you are not good at it. Just like this Open Letter. &lt;a href=&#34;http://tekpub.com&#34;&gt;Tekpub&lt;/a&gt; is wonderful endeavor from &lt;a href=&#34;http://wekeroad.com/&#34;&gt;Rob Conery&lt;/a&gt; and one of his friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://averyblog.com/&#34;&gt;James Avery&lt;/a&gt; . I know &lt;a href=&#34;http://tekpub.com&#34;&gt;Tekpub&lt;/a&gt; because of &lt;a href=&#34;http://wekeroad.com/&#34;&gt;Rob Conery&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can consider me in his fan club, if he is having one. I don’t know of it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, Rob. Do you have any fan club like thing ??? I really like to join one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in India, every other teacher expect student to be like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arjuna&#34;&gt;Arjuna&lt;/a&gt; , because of his concentration and dedication towards the learning or work. But the person they forget is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ekalavya&#34;&gt;Ekalavya&lt;/a&gt; . And Rob sir is providing that opportunity to world to learn like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ekalavya&#34;&gt;Ekalavya&lt;/a&gt; . Learning from distance and prove your worthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tekpub.com&#34;&gt;Tekpub&lt;/a&gt; is having open house for a weekend. And first thing I have done is watching a video of a programming wizard, genius developer and classic speaker &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; . I was waiting for this from a long time. Actually I am saving money to buy at least this video, because here we have currency in rupees and conversion to dollar is bit heavy on pocket. No doubt I am earning fair enough as software engineer but still amount is a more in terms of rupees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are not the only thing, I am currently checking out few more screen casts. And they are awesome. I always in favor of knowledge sharing. And may be this is the only reason to have a dream to work in Microsoft. Money obviously matters, but that I can earn it any how. At the end of the day I am from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gujarat&#34;&gt;Gujarat&lt;/a&gt; . But knowledge, learning new things and specially having fun at what I do; will be possible at few places only. It is not about Microsoft but about persons like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/&#34;&gt;Phil Haack&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;http://wekeroad.com/&#34;&gt;Rob Conery&lt;/a&gt; and others. Working with them is seriously a fun stuff, its like you are learning from a university and also getting paid for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, Scott Sir. In any case you are reading this. Please Please do take care of your self. At least buy me some time so I can meet you in person someday in future. Diabetes called as “Rajarog” in India. Means it only comes to king and/or it is king of all diseases as it provide wonderful platform for other diseases to have dance off. So, please do take care and keep on talking. I never miss your screen cast or talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seriously like to thank Rob and Team for bringing up such a wonderful world of knowledge. And also having open pass to access them on weekend. Keep on the good work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seriously recommended that wasting time for some box office flicks, better enjoy heroes from Technology world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks of Open House at &lt;a href=&#34;http://tekpub.com&#34;&gt;Tekpub&lt;/a&gt; . And thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluralsight-training.net&#34;&gt;pluralsight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kunjan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>