<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fsharp on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/fsharp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fsharp on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/fsharp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elmish Xamarin Forms from Fable point of View</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2018/08/elmish-xamarin-forms-from-fable-point-of-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2018/08/elmish-xamarin-forms-from-fable-point-of-view/</guid>
      <description>Elm and Elmish patterns is kind of new cool in web world. Good people in F# put that Elmish in Xamarin Forms.
 Immutable UI for Xamarin forms.
 That is quite bold in it self. We will look at Pros and Cons of it in this post and also try to look EXF from angle of other contemporary technologies for creating cross platform mobile application.
One thing I like to clarify before moving forward,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated Fable2 - Architecture &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2018/08/opinionated-fable2-architecture-and-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2018/08/opinionated-fable2-architecture-and-performance/</guid>
      <description>Nothing can be more beautiful if you wish come. And It seems Fable2 did made my wish true in most of the cases. Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit my old blog and check what is got improved and changed. So, goal of this blog is it should be same as old blog, but it should be smaller. Because of new and shiny Fable2.
 Fable 2 is currently in beta but as per blog it is very much working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated Fable - Architecture &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2018/03/opinionated-fable-architecture-and-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2018/03/opinionated-fable-architecture-and-performance/</guid>
      <description>There can&amp;rsquo;t be better time for writing this blog. As Fable 2.0 is on the horizon it would be good to see what 1.0 already can do. And I can also wish few things to be added to 2.0.
I have chosen Fable after evaluating couple of options like TypeScript-React-Redux, Elm, Aurelia, Angular. One thing I was pretty much sure that I wanted static typing in my project. Because I did have first hand experience with big fat Angular application built using JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Chat application using ServiceStack and Fable in F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Here is my Birthday blog post, as a part of FSAdvent - 2017. Just like previous two years, I hope you will enjoy this one too. Comments and corrections are very much welcomed.
 Why Chaat? and What is Chaat? If anyone wanted to show real time application, then Chat is kind of to-do list of that type of applications. Now Functional Chat is a very limited title and can&amp;rsquo;t show all the things I wanted to show.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>