<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Chaat with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Why Chaat? and What is Chaat? Most of us - developers like two things more than anything; eating (,cooking for some) and coding. So, I like to talk about one of the favorite dishes; Indian Chaat. Yup, it is more about F# and also part of fsAdvent calendar 2017. So, why this specific dish??? To understand that you should try searching French Onion Soup or Pizzas and then Search for Indian Chaat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic Adventure using F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2016/12/epic-adventure-using-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2016/12/epic-adventure-using-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>This article is part of FSAdvent 2016 calendar.
This my second post of 2016. Sadly not much of writing this year. So, I need to cover up by this little longish post. So, grab your favorite coffee / tea before getting started.
There is one wonderful coincidence here that both post of 2016 is based on Epic Mahabharata. If anyone interested in poem like things do check out my another post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Identity</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2016/04/my-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2016/04/my-identity/</guid>
      <description>Few words dedicated to people who made me who I am right now, my teachers. I know few of them personally and few others I am yet to meet in person. But they are still there always for me. Guiding me and helping me whenever and wherever I need. Words are not enough to say Thanks but still here with my small try
Here is original Gujarati Version
જેને કોઈ ઓળખની જરૂર નથી</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1729</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/12/1729/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/12/1729/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of F# Advent calender. Thanks Sergey Tihon for arranging this and giving me chance.
 First I like to clarify that this was not my original choice for FSAdvent calender. I was going to write long post about web, AKKA, api and real time system. My current working area. But this time&amp;rsquo;s calender entries are reaching new level and dimension. And recent post from Evelina Gabasova is kind of reason behind change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Services with Servicestack and F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/reactive-services-with-servicestack-and-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/reactive-services-with-servicestack-and-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Reactive word is not new nowadays. If you want your library to get limelight, use reactive word in the name any way possible and it will definitely get initial attention. Reactive word is appropriate for things that follows reactive manifesto. That is true for now. And there are many variant of libraries on server and client to fulfil this.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the start of web.
We were having old web were we used to do post event of page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure web sites with Paket</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/azure-web-sites-with-paket/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/azure-web-sites-with-paket/</guid>
      <description>Whoever worked with Microsoft Shop knows about nuget. It is package manager for anything and everything related to .Net. And it is getting better and better with versions coming in. But again it is nowhere near maturity needed to work with projects having many small projects. Things get cranky soon.
Now, there is better option as per my opinion called Paket. Very easy to get started. And so damn reliable. Couple of more command to learn but I guess it is ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angularjs and the Mess we are in</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know Angularjs?!? Everyone worked is web, mobile, server, windows, mac, Linux, Google, Microsoft or anyway related to this knows about it. And its fun when people tell me
 You know about angularjs. Its pretty hot now a days. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to learn it.
 Oh man&amp;hellip;
Ok I am no expert here in Angularjs. And I prefer not to be expert with any framework. Be it anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Command Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-command-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-command-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Command pattern is a pattern which allows executor of the pattern to execute or playback the commands. In most of the application wherever Undo/Redo is implemented this pattern is used.
Here is C# code.
 Now, in this code Command Pattern is not in its purest form. As, normally in command pattern we are saving state of outside object. Instead I just returned the result to mock out side object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Strategy Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-strategy-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-strategy-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Another pattern that is widely used in Object Oriented world. And as far as .Net world is concern it is may be most used pattern in wide range of .Net API. And it heavily used in heavily used LINQ API.
So, I guess giving a understanding of that is kinda waste of space. Have a look at C# code.
 People familiar with LINQ and lovers of Lambda will definitely argue that this is can be replaced by delegates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Singleton Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-singleton-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-singleton-pattern/</guid>
      <description>This is my favorite pattern. First pattern I learn. And till date I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to use it. So, I use everywhere. :P
I have mainly used for database connection object and then all JavaScript frameworks are exposing Singleton object only. I can say it is quite useful in case of web.
Fun part about this pattern is that most of the people including me always use this pattern to show off that we know patterns and we follow it in practice but in most cases that practice starts and stops with Singleton Pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Factory Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-factory-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-factory-pattern/</guid>
      <description>The fun part working or explaining functional pattern is word functional can be used in very fun way. Just like it is used in title here.
Now, factory pattern may be the most used pattern in Object Oriented world. Here is code in C#.
 Factory method is basically used to abstract away the object creation. I am not worried how object is created but I am worried about the behavior of the objects that are created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Design Pattern in a Functional Way</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/demystifying-design-pattern-in-a-functional-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/demystifying-design-pattern-in-a-functional-way/</guid>
      <description>As functional programming is taking pace in current software development. There is always a question what is the difference and why on the earth I should bother about it.
Most of the time reason of the question comes because of human nature of resistance towards learning new things. And then there are people who can easily learn new things but even for them unlearning something and re-learning new things is pretty tough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey in Search of Destination</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/03/journey-in-search-of-destination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/03/journey-in-search-of-destination/</guid>
      <description>I never thought I would make this public. I wrote long back for one of my dear cousin. It was relevant then. But it is more relevant now. One of my best friend, batch mate, college mate, colleague at one point of time, rommie is now moving to another country. With a aim to never looking back for all the good reasons.
Andrew Vyas this is for you. You are one of the friend I never wanted because I knew one day time flew and you or me will move on and that may be good for future but at point it is utterly painful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typed Hack of Cloudant using F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>There is a continues war between typed and untyped data. But then there is need of finding a middle ground for ever growing application. There is place, a requirement when I feel application should be typed and data store should be untyped. So, I created this little code snippet to access cloudant (a couchbase fork) NOSQL database.
I was knowing about Cloudant from long back. Even before IBM bought it. It is indeed a wonderful service and also kinda free for small stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sails sailing seamlessly on Azure Web Sites</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of frameworks for web development in Nodejs. Many of them are pretty cool. I pretty much like the SailsJS. And also have worked on that in recent past.
Now, when it comes to hosting I love the Azure for various reasons. It is specially awesome when it comes to web sites. You do some experiments and throw it towards azure and that is ready for world to check out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Xamarin with Love</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/to-xamarin-with-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/to-xamarin-with-love/</guid>
      <description>Xamarin Evolve just concluded. And there no best time to write this post. And for the fact I am not writing anything new or even anything related to announcements that happened there. I am writing this because recently I got chance to work with android using Java. And experience was not at all good. And reason is not so surprisingly Java.
I am will not explain anything instead I just copy paste three code snippets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web programming and F# still a Far Cry?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</guid>
      <description>F# is wonderful language. And luckily or unluckily I do Web Programming (now a days mostly that). So, it is always a preference to use it, wherever possible. But even in 2014 end it is still pain in a**.
I did make templates for Servicestack and I will continue to support that. But when it comes to real projects they go far beyond templates.
I recently experimenting on something and obviously I am gonna use templates created by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My broken marriage with C# and extramarital affair with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>*NOTE- As per today I am neither married nor committed. And for that case never married and never committed. :P*
 Whoever is following my progress must be knowing my love for F#. Neither me nor F# knows exact time and date when that happen. But now it is like if few days I have to pass without writing few lines to(in) F# then it felt like I have left software engineering for good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Servciestack with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>This may be nastiest thing I have done with deployment after a long time. There is no problem with making it work. But deployment on azure is a serious issue. And luckily I completed that. Yes, there is a luck involved.
If you read my previous entry for running Nancy and SignalR together. Then most of the things are same only.
Use Servicestack template to create project. Remove global.asax &amp;amp; global.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xamarin Studio 3 - First Look</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamarin-studio-3---first-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamarin-studio-3---first-look/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I got mail from Xamarin about their launch of new IDE. And also for the registration of webinar. And just like always they again managed to blow my mind. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what else they are having for upcoming evolve conference..
Xamarin is like technical democracy. &amp;gt; A company of Technical People, by the technical people and for the technical people.
A kinda awesome. Just like their new studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to wonderful community</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</guid>
      <description>Few days back Scott Hanselman tweeted
Take a moment, right now, and email the organizers of your favorite Open Source project and THANK THEM.
&amp;mdash; Scott Hanselman (@shanselman) April 15, 2014 
And I think, I should do that. But twitter is too short and emails boring even I don&amp;rsquo;t have email ids of few of my favourite Open Source project managers. But I am not shying away from thanking. So, I am writing this entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Nancy with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>What you feel if you meet your favourite actor? Feeling is wonderful right? Now, add the your actress in the mixture. Have you said WOW??? How about director? Still heart is beating?!? How about having dinner with them? Nothing can be better than that.
I am having kinda same feeling. It is nothing new that Nancy is dancing quite comfortable with F#. And thanks to Daniel Mohl we are also having templates to get started with Nancy and F#.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I moved away from Sencha to Phonejs?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</guid>
      <description>Sencha is well known framework for mobile development. Not only mobile development but it is doing a hell of a lot of thing other than mobile development. Not only that it is surely having wonderful history with JavaScript framework development. I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to complain against that.
But today I am going to talk about specifically one framework, that is Sencha Touch. I was trying to something that can developed once and deployed everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failed attempt to write series, again!</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/failed-attempt-to-write-series-again/</guid>
      <description>I have tried writing complete series again. And again failed. And I am stopping it again.
There are couple of reason of it. First and for most thing is I am not good at it. No where near even readable, I guess. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t know reason specifically for that. May be I can write on specific topic better instead of things that are continues.
And that is the reason complete series thing is not that good but individual write ups are getting good reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servicestack F# template. Starting from the Start</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</guid>
      <description>I have already wrote a blog post about how to get started with service stack if any one is using templates. It is pretty easy. Just install and run.
But as Service Stack is moved to V4 with some breaking changes. I had give details about updating it. But still it is little bit more complicated or confusing if I can say.
@kunjee Sure, otherwise a tutorial on getting SS v4 + F# together without templates would be better than starting from a broken v3 one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servicestack F# template Update. Circle is Complete</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-update-circle-is-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-update-circle-is-complete/</guid>
      <description>Few day&amp;rsquo;s back I wrote a article about how I created side waffle templates for Servicestack.
Yesterday, Daniel Mohl, merged the pull request. Add the missing bits make it working and it is up on visual studio gallery. I seriously like to thank Daniel for this work and support even after his own hectic schedule of day job. And a wonderful members of F# community.
Here, I am sharing few details of the template, I have created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Servicestack meet F# via Side Waffle</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/when-servicestack-meet-fsharp-via-side-waffle/</guid>
      <description>I have specific love for Servicestack and that is known thing. It is not because it is awesome or the ways it do web service things, no one else is doing. But because of my past with WCF. It is so rocky that I never want to go back. And more over Servicestack doing hell lot of the things under the cover, and that is also without doing any damn thing into XML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.Net MVC5 with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/asp.net-mvc5-with-f/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Danial Mohl getting started with Asp.net MVC5 is pretty easy. He had put a tremendous effort to make different kind of templates. Even starting from MVC3 till date now.
Old templates are like there are two projects one is C# and one is F#. C# is having all the Java Script, html, css and stuff while F# is having coding part.
But with time pass and version update, now we are having pure F# templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Functional web</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/getting-started-with-functional-web/</guid>
      <description>I am doing web development from quite a long time. And now a days I am keep pushing my self to do functional programming. Learning languages like Haskell, Scala, F#. Obviously I try my hand to other functional languages too as per time permits.
As I am .Net developer my primary focused is working with F# and I will also start from that only. You can also check out other functional articles of mine to check out what I think about functional programming and why it is necessity now a days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I continue writing more poems?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/should-i-continue-writing-more-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/should-i-continue-writing-more-poems/</guid>
      <description>Long back I have tried my hand to writing poems. And trust me I am no where near poetic part. I have good grip over language but that is only for my mother tongue. I am quite comfortable with English but still no where near having artistic touch. Or in simple language my database of words is not that strong. But normally I am able to convey my feelings.
I can say, I am pretty lucky in the case of writing poems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming Need in Web Development</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/12/functional-programming-need-in-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/12/functional-programming-need-in-web-development/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I talk about Functional Programming people with experience in web make faces. And seriously don&amp;rsquo;t blame them.
Issue is mainly Functional Programming stays in back ground only. If you see any starting example of any functional language is mainly some machine learning example or some complicated algorithm example. And that may effect normal people to getting started with Functional Programming.
But functional programming can do far more than that. And that include simple things too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developer without Programming Language</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/11/a-developer-without-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/11/a-developer-without-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>Now a days I am little bit more involved in History lessons. And those also from Computer Science only. Specifically from programming language&amp;rsquo;s perspective. Why on the earth I am doing this, I guess answer is given by Duglas Cockford over the Hanselminutes. And personally I love this part of learning. It is so delightful to know different language and why languages emerge the way it is.
That is one part of story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming, How I started and Why?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/10/functional-programming-how-i-started-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/10/functional-programming-how-i-started-and-why/</guid>
      <description>I am not kind of Technical person who started hacking / coding in very early age. But I have special love / affection towards numbers. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why but it always fascinate me.
And this was the starting point or I can say reason I started baby steps in functional programming. I like DI, not in term of Dependency Injection but in case of Data Interpretation. Those tabular data and all the graphs and details that data can produce is awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes, I like functional programming</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/i-like-functional-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/i-like-functional-programming/</guid>
      <description>Because it is good. It is fun to write code in functional language. It takes away unnecessary complexity from my way. It do as problem needed I don&amp;rsquo;t need to act as computer to give instruction to computer for how to do computing.
 And just like this specific blog, it is concise, crisp and like haiku short and sweet.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Ruby on Rails in not only for Ruby on Rails Developers?!</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/why-ruby-on-rails-in-not-only-for-ruby-on-rails-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/why-ruby-on-rails-in-not-only-for-ruby-on-rails-developers/</guid>
      <description>If you ever involved in web development, then you must be knowing the history of it. Once upon a time there is something called CGI. And at that moment there are static html pages.
Only few part of page is dynamic. Then things changed, ASP came. Server access become so normal and easy. But still there is a lot more work to do. And main issue with them is code is not arranged and coding style is not suitable for big projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIM for me?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/vim-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/vim-for-me/</guid>
      <description>I want confess that, my whole career I was and I am working with Visual Studio. Not a big fan, but it was good or I must say it is good. I don&amp;rsquo;t think any other IDE is doing as much thing as visual studio is doing.
And with few add-ons (even if you exclude ReSharper) it is like wow. As full time web developer I like the tools, that always there to solve my issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Business</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/back-to-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/back-to-business/</guid>
      <description>It have been long that I was doing active blogging. There are multiple reason for that, and on of them is being a lazy ass.
I changed my blog from Orchard to Docpad for almost no reason. I just wanted my few page look different then other pages. And that will little bit more effort if I am going to do it with Orchard. So, I check out on net how to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entity Framework Upside Down</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/12/entity-framework-upside-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/12/entity-framework-upside-down/</guid>
      <description>If you have read my previous articles you must be knowing that I don’t like ORMs that much and also I am pretty lazy person. I don’t like to repeat stuff again and again. If I can find the solution than I will automate it or I just change from very root. Same thing is true with Entity Framework. It comes after LINQ to SQL as an improved ORM. And it proved to be lousy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Never Changed!!! Guiding Principles to Software Development</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/11/something-never-changed-guiding-principals-to-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/11/something-never-changed-guiding-principals-to-software-development/</guid>
      <description>I am particularly a lazy guy. I don’t work hard, stay back and never show sad face to issue or bug. Obviously many don’t like me for this. But again “who cares?”. But one thing is sure for me, I always ready to learn new things and obviously always work for better code. At the end of day it is just a code, bugs will be there and me too , to solve the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duffer&#39;s guide for windows 8 installation</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/duffers-guide-for-windows-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/duffers-guide-for-windows-installation/</guid>
      <description>Oops, I used “Duffer” instead of “Dummy” because I am one of it.
I installed OS nearly 8 times to get what I wanted from Windows 8. I brought new Dell Ultra book and first thing I have done is to install consumer preview, second thing installing VS2012. And I meet my first issue, it is not allowed so I need to use trial version, so another format and new OS in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Casting JavaScript with Typescript</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/type-casting-javascript-with-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/type-casting-javascript-with-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Whenever something came from Microsoft or Microsoft employee there is always a buzz… And I still don’t understand why person’s company policies do with person’s attitude or approach of a person. Same happens when typescript came. It was just a day old and Open Source People starts bashing it like anything. Comparing with CoffeeScript , Dart . Guys, it is also open source and Microsoft in any case not forcing anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Diary II</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-ii/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I have written about some JavaScript basics from the point of view of Software Engineering and Architecture. In this post I will stay close to metal. I will talk about few things we should care about JavaScript language. Things that’s should be or shouldn’t be in the code.
I am from hard core compile language background. My first company is Game Company where I have built kind of Game Engine and second company I work on C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Diary I</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/09/javascript-diary-i/</guid>
      <description>Long back I have wrote a article on CoffeeScript . If anyone see closely its all about writing proper Java Script in easy way. But in many cases its not possible that you got chance to write CoffeeScript . Or if you are learning some library like KnockoutJS or BackboneJS , also if you are using some framework like AngularJS . Than using CoffeeScript and also using this function to learn than it will be difficult to catch up together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Miss You Sister</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/</guid>
      <description>First friend I found was you
First enemy I found was you
First fight I had was with you
First person I always miss is you
I miss you, my dear sister
Beating me was your favorite game
Teasing me with different names
Remaining is now, only the pain
Not being with you, I feel mundane
I miss you, my dear sister
You are Dad’s favorite
You are Mom’s favorite</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee with CoffeeScript</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/coffee-with-coffeescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/coffee-with-coffeescript/</guid>
      <description>I am in Bangalore, and first thing I found here classically well is coffee. Obviously I will not going to talk about coffee here. But about CoffeeScript which is as good as coffee . I come to know about CoffeeScript from the article written by Scott Hanselman . And I become addicted to it. I am not much a web guy. I like coding but mostly on server end. And Visual Studio is always there to save me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open letter to Tekpub</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/open-letter-to-tekpub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/open-letter-to-tekpub/</guid>
      <description>I am not much a writer kind of person. If you drop a math puzzle, probably I will do it in better way. But sometimes it is necessity to do thing even though you are not good at it. Just like this Open Letter. Tekpub is wonderful endeavor from Rob Conery and one of his friend James Avery . I know Tekpub because of Rob Conery .
You can consider me in his fan club, if he is having one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving away from OOP</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/03/moving-away-from-oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/03/moving-away-from-oop/</guid>
      <description>OOP, it is a full form of Object Oriented Programming. And even with starting of career in software engineering we are force to implement OOP in our coding. Cross your heart and tell how many time we are implementing???
I start my career with .Net / C#. And C# is object oriented language. But I code like C. Pushing function for every thing. May be it is my love for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive Effect</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/massive-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/massive-effect/</guid>
      <description>Hope you have read my earlier post about Micro ORM . Here I talk about another Micro ORM Massive . I don’t want to go with traditional approach. I write intro about Rob Conery and give some details about Massive . Few example here and there, some hyperlinks and that’s it. I will try to find answer of “why” instead of “how”. For how part we have more than enough example and also have stackoverflow to solve issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrival of David aka Micro Orm</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/arrival-of-david-aka-micro-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/arrival-of-david-aka-micro-orm/</guid>
      <description>If you have read my previous post . I have talk about how ORM can create mess with the application. And prior to that I have write that it speed up the production like anything.
 So, Am I contradicting my self ???
 No, I am just learning new things. I am using ORM but now I am more careful while using it. That’s it.
 So, why Vietnam ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to Vietnam Because of ORM</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/going-to-vietnam-because-of-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/going-to-vietnam-because-of-orm/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I have talk about ORM . But believe if you don’t use thing wisely you are going to fall like anything. In this article I am not going to write any code but still it is a pure technical article. I will talk about enterprise application and how quickly love for ORM will drag you to the black hole.
Around two years back, at the time when .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map your self using ORM</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/map-your-self-using-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/map-your-self-using-orm/</guid>
      <description>Many of you must know this word, “ORM”. Then why this post. But trust, even after we have a lots and lots of ORMs in market and some company still using age old technology. Just few days back in one company again I had to face same old question about connection class and command class. Why?????????? It is so true that one must know that things, but this question is always be a nightmare to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuget mall of OSS</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/nuget-mall-of-oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/nuget-mall-of-oss/</guid>
      <description>OSS, stands for Open Source Software. If you are a .net developer, most of the time you don’t care much of OSS. But trust me, OSS are far better than pure solution provided by MS.
And now MS is pushing for OSS, via nuget . It’s a wonderful site providing base for OSS technologies. If you have experienced development in Ruby, you must have known this. Ruby has gems, which pushed by open source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bhagwad Gita Chapter 1</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>कुर्क्षेत्र की युद्ध भूमि पर सैन्य निरिक्षण
Its all started when war of Mahabharata is about to begin. Both army stand against each other. And at the time of war, Arjuna told Krishna to take his chariot to the middle of battle field. When they reach there, Arjuna observed both side of army.
At this time he found only relatives on the both side. And he just collapsed. He don’t want to fight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bhagwad Gita Introduction</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Who ever know something about Indian culture must have know about Gita. As per religion or history whatever you prefer, it is a compilation of words, a message given to Arjuna by Krishna. It is not only for him but for whole world. And trust me this book do have answer of almost any things.
First I brief about this compilation. At the time of Mahabharata war, when Arjuna has to face his own family at war place, kurukshetra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test your self before test your code</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/test-your-self-before-test-your-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/test-your-self-before-test-your-code/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I had written a post , on Test Driven Development . And many of my friends raise question, why should I test and is there anything there in built in Visual Studio. And also more explanation on Test Driven Design. So, Here again I will some what more deeper in testing. Ok, its just a little bit deeper.
First thing, as per title, you should test your self before test your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DI of FDI (Foreign direct investment)</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/di-of-fdi-foreign-direct-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/di-of-fdi-foreign-direct-investment/</guid>
      <description>It has been a week or so, every day news paper and news channel are full with news of FDI in India . Even Facebook is not taking a step back and speak in favor of both side. FDI in retails should be allowed or not.
I am not a politician, so as engineer I will do data analysis of FDI in India. now, for the sake of example we consider that FDI is allowed in retail market (PS : I personally think that it is going to be allowed) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey of Coder to Developer</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/11/journey-of-coder-to-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/11/journey-of-coder-to-developer/</guid>
      <description>I had seen one T-shirt where developer and programmer are erased coder is written below it. I just remember that and was thinking, why so.
Answer is just with me. Every time we start work, and first thing we do is to hit Google. Copy and paste code and make things work. Never bother our self why code is working like that only and why I am copying this only. 60 people out of 100 are doing the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for your Smile</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/11/waiting-for-your-smile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/11/waiting-for-your-smile/</guid>
      <description>Its wonderful morning
Sun is waiting to rise
It’s waiting for you sun shine
Waiting for your wonderful smile
Birds wake up
Songs are waiting to be sung
Beats are waiting for you sun shine
Waiting for your dazzling smile
Air just started moving
Breeze just wanted to spread
Fragrance is waiting for you sun shine
Waiting for your mesmerizing smile
Pen is ready to write
Ink is desperate to draw</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOA Service Oriented Architecture Beginning of New Era</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/soa-service-oriented-architecture-beginning-of-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/soa-service-oriented-architecture-beginning-of-new-era/</guid>
      <description>Web services is not new to computer world, it is in use from long back. But now a day, with electronic revolution we have lot more devices with loaded application. We want everything everywhere. We need access of facebook from PC, from mobile, from Tablet.
Everyone has more than one email id, and want to be online at once.Chatting with friends on gmail , hotmail , aol , yahoo , ICQ , facebook , linkedin and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pointers what is your address dude</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/pointers-what-is-your-address-dude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/pointers-what-is-your-address-dude/</guid>
      <description>Pointers, heart of C, C++. If you belongs to engineering branch and learned C as subject, then this may be the last chapter of you curriculum. This is the stepping stone of programming career. This is the chapter or I can say love for the pointer will differentiate a passionate coder from normal coder.
Even if you work, higher level languages or going for web, you can’t deny existence of pointer in your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot of Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/snapshot-of-steve-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/snapshot-of-steve-jobs/</guid>
      <description>I was reading article on Wall Street Journal , about Steve Jobs. It was wonderful article taken by Ralph, at time of starting phase of apple.
It was the time of change, if any one is familiar with the history of&amp;nbsp; computer world, must know the era of changing. When companies like Microsoft and Apple started and change the rule of game. They change the way of thinking that computer should be big and for co-operate work only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structure through C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/data-stucture-through-cpp-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/data-stucture-through-cpp-review/</guid>
      <description>Whoever is ever being engaged with computer science field, they have to come across the term data structure. Even a simple user, using Google , Bing and other search engine, using Facebook for social networking, they all touched by basic fundamental of computers, called data structure. Also, every Computer Science branch has this as part of curriculum.
Here is the one of the best book I found for this. Book called Data Structure Through C++ , wonderfully written book by Yashvant Kanetkar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>