<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oss on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/oss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oss on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/oss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated Fable - Architecture &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2018/03/opinionated-fable-architecture-and-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2018/03/opinionated-fable-architecture-and-performance/</guid>
      <description>There can&amp;rsquo;t be better time for writing this blog. As Fable 2.0 is on the horizon it would be good to see what 1.0 already can do. And I can also wish few things to be added to 2.0.
I have chosen Fable after evaluating couple of options like TypeScript-React-Redux, Elm, Aurelia, Angular. One thing I was pretty much sure that I wanted static typing in my project. Because I did have first hand experience with big fat Angular application built using JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Chaat with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2017/12/indian-chaat-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Here is my Birthday blog post, as a part of FSAdvent - 2017. Just like previous two years, I hope you will enjoy this one too. Comments and corrections are very much welcomed.
 Why Chaat? and What is Chaat? If anyone wanted to show real time application, then Chat is kind of to-do list of that type of applications. Now Functional Chat is a very limited title and can&amp;rsquo;t show all the things I wanted to show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1729</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/12/1729/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/12/1729/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of F# Advent calender. Thanks Sergey Tihon for arranging this and giving me chance.
 First I like to clarify that this was not my original choice for FSAdvent calender. I was going to write long post about web, AKKA, api and real time system. My current working area. But this time&amp;rsquo;s calender entries are reaching new level and dimension. And recent post from Evelina Gabasova is kind of reason behind change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Services with Servicestack and F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/reactive-services-with-servicestack-and-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/reactive-services-with-servicestack-and-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Reactive word is not new nowadays. If you want your library to get limelight, use reactive word in the name any way possible and it will definitely get initial attention. Reactive word is appropriate for things that follows reactive manifesto. That is true for now. And there are many variant of libraries on server and client to fulfil this.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the start of web.
We were having old web were we used to do post event of page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure web sites with Paket</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/azure-web-sites-with-paket/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/azure-web-sites-with-paket/</guid>
      <description>Whoever worked with Microsoft Shop knows about nuget. It is package manager for anything and everything related to .Net. And it is getting better and better with versions coming in. But again it is nowhere near maturity needed to work with projects having many small projects. Things get cranky soon.
Now, there is better option as per my opinion called Paket. Very easy to get started. And so damn reliable. Couple of more command to learn but I guess it is ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angularjs and the Mess we are in</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/11/angularjs-and-the-mess-we-are-in/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know Angularjs?!? Everyone worked is web, mobile, server, windows, mac, Linux, Google, Microsoft or anyway related to this knows about it. And its fun when people tell me
 You know about angularjs. Its pretty hot now a days. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to learn it.
 Oh man&amp;hellip;
Ok I am no expert here in Angularjs. And I prefer not to be expert with any framework. Be it anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Command Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-command-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-command-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Command pattern is a pattern which allows executor of the pattern to execute or playback the commands. In most of the application wherever Undo/Redo is implemented this pattern is used.
Here is C# code.
 Now, in this code Command Pattern is not in its purest form. As, normally in command pattern we are saving state of outside object. Instead I just returned the result to mock out side object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Strategy Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-strategy-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-strategy-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Another pattern that is widely used in Object Oriented world. And as far as .Net world is concern it is may be most used pattern in wide range of .Net API. And it heavily used in heavily used LINQ API.
So, I guess giving a understanding of that is kinda waste of space. Have a look at C# code.
 People familiar with LINQ and lovers of Lambda will definitely argue that this is can be replaced by delegates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Singleton Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-singleton-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-singleton-pattern/</guid>
      <description>This is my favorite pattern. First pattern I learn. And till date I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to use it. So, I use everywhere. :P
I have mainly used for database connection object and then all JavaScript frameworks are exposing Singleton object only. I can say it is quite useful in case of web.
Fun part about this pattern is that most of the people including me always use this pattern to show off that we know patterns and we follow it in practice but in most cases that practice starts and stops with Singleton Pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Factory Pattern</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-factory-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/functional-factory-pattern/</guid>
      <description>The fun part working or explaining functional pattern is word functional can be used in very fun way. Just like it is used in title here.
Now, factory pattern may be the most used pattern in Object Oriented world. Here is code in C#.
 Factory method is basically used to abstract away the object creation. I am not worried how object is created but I am worried about the behavior of the objects that are created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Design Pattern in a Functional Way</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/demystifying-design-pattern-in-a-functional-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/04/demystifying-design-pattern-in-a-functional-way/</guid>
      <description>As functional programming is taking pace in current software development. There is always a question what is the difference and why on the earth I should bother about it.
Most of the time reason of the question comes because of human nature of resistance towards learning new things. And then there are people who can easily learn new things but even for them unlearning something and re-learning new things is pretty tough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typed Hack of Cloudant using F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/typed-hack-of-cloudant-using-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>There is a continues war between typed and untyped data. But then there is need of finding a middle ground for ever growing application. There is place, a requirement when I feel application should be typed and data store should be untyped. So, I created this little code snippet to access cloudant (a couchbase fork) NOSQL database.
I was knowing about Cloudant from long back. Even before IBM bought it. It is indeed a wonderful service and also kinda free for small stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sails sailing seamlessly on Azure Web Sites</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/11/sails-sailing-seamlessly-on-azure-web-sites/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of frameworks for web development in Nodejs. Many of them are pretty cool. I pretty much like the SailsJS. And also have worked on that in recent past.
Now, when it comes to hosting I love the Azure for various reasons. It is specially awesome when it comes to web sites. You do some experiments and throw it towards azure and that is ready for world to check out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Xamarin with Love</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/to-xamarin-with-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/to-xamarin-with-love/</guid>
      <description>Xamarin Evolve just concluded. And there no best time to write this post. And for the fact I am not writing anything new or even anything related to announcements that happened there. I am writing this because recently I got chance to work with android using Java. And experience was not at all good. And reason is not so surprisingly Java.
I am will not explain anything instead I just copy paste three code snippets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web programming and F# still a Far Cry?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</guid>
      <description>F# is wonderful language. And luckily or unluckily I do Web Programming (now a days mostly that). So, it is always a preference to use it, wherever possible. But even in 2014 end it is still pain in a**.
I did make templates for Servicestack and I will continue to support that. But when it comes to real projects they go far beyond templates.
I recently experimenting on something and obviously I am gonna use templates created by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My broken marriage with C# and extramarital affair with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>*NOTE- As per today I am neither married nor committed. And for that case never married and never committed. :P*
 Whoever is following my progress must be knowing my love for F#. Neither me nor F# knows exact time and date when that happen. But now it is like if few days I have to pass without writing few lines to(in) F# then it felt like I have left software engineering for good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Servciestack with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>This may be nastiest thing I have done with deployment after a long time. There is no problem with making it work. But deployment on azure is a serious issue. And luckily I completed that. Yes, there is a luck involved.
If you read my previous entry for running Nancy and SignalR together. Then most of the things are same only.
Use Servicestack template to create project. Remove global.asax &amp;amp; global.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xamarin Studio 3 - First Look</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamarin-studio-3---first-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamarin-studio-3---first-look/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I got mail from Xamarin about their launch of new IDE. And also for the registration of webinar. And just like always they again managed to blow my mind. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what else they are having for upcoming evolve conference..
Xamarin is like technical democracy. &amp;gt; A company of Technical People, by the technical people and for the technical people.
A kinda awesome. Just like their new studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to wonderful community</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</guid>
      <description>Few days back Scott Hanselman tweeted
Take a moment, right now, and email the organizers of your favorite Open Source project and THANK THEM.
&amp;mdash; Scott Hanselman (@shanselman) April 15, 2014 
And I think, I should do that. But twitter is too short and emails boring even I don&amp;rsquo;t have email ids of few of my favourite Open Source project managers. But I am not shying away from thanking. So, I am writing this entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Nancy with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>What you feel if you meet your favourite actor? Feeling is wonderful right? Now, add the your actress in the mixture. Have you said WOW??? How about director? Still heart is beating?!? How about having dinner with them? Nothing can be better than that.
I am having kinda same feeling. It is nothing new that Nancy is dancing quite comfortable with F#. And thanks to Daniel Mohl we are also having templates to get started with Nancy and F#.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I moved away from Sencha to Phonejs?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</guid>
      <description>Sencha is well known framework for mobile development. Not only mobile development but it is doing a hell of a lot of thing other than mobile development. Not only that it is surely having wonderful history with JavaScript framework development. I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to complain against that.
But today I am going to talk about specifically one framework, that is Sencha Touch. I was trying to something that can developed once and deployed everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servicestack F# template. Starting from the Start</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</guid>
      <description>I have already wrote a blog post about how to get started with service stack if any one is using templates. It is pretty easy. Just install and run.
But as Service Stack is moved to V4 with some breaking changes. I had give details about updating it. But still it is little bit more complicated or confusing if I can say.
@kunjee Sure, otherwise a tutorial on getting SS v4 + F# together without templates would be better than starting from a broken v3 one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servicestack F# template Update. Circle is Complete</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-update-circle-is-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-update-circle-is-complete/</guid>
      <description>Few day&amp;rsquo;s back I wrote a article about how I created side waffle templates for Servicestack.
Yesterday, Daniel Mohl, merged the pull request. Add the missing bits make it working and it is up on visual studio gallery. I seriously like to thank Daniel for this work and support even after his own hectic schedule of day job. And a wonderful members of F# community.
Here, I am sharing few details of the template, I have created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming Need in Web Development</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/12/functional-programming-need-in-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/12/functional-programming-need-in-web-development/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I talk about Functional Programming people with experience in web make faces. And seriously don&amp;rsquo;t blame them.
Issue is mainly Functional Programming stays in back ground only. If you see any starting example of any functional language is mainly some machine learning example or some complicated algorithm example. And that may effect normal people to getting started with Functional Programming.
But functional programming can do far more than that. And that include simple things too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrival of David aka Micro Orm</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/arrival-of-david-aka-micro-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/arrival-of-david-aka-micro-orm/</guid>
      <description>If you have read my previous post . I have talk about how ORM can create mess with the application. And prior to that I have write that it speed up the production like anything.
 So, Am I contradicting my self ???
 No, I am just learning new things. I am using ORM but now I am more careful while using it. That’s it.
 So, why Vietnam ?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>