<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/categories/non-technical/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/categories/non-technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Identity</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2016/04/my-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2016/04/my-identity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few words dedicated to people who made me who I am right now, my teachers. I know few of them personally and few others I am yet to meet in person. But they are still there always for me. Guiding me and helping me whenever and wherever I need. Words are not enough to say Thanks but still here with my small try&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is original Gujarati Version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;જેને કોઈ ઓળખની જરૂર નથી&lt;br /&gt;
જેની પ્રતિષ્ઠા ચંદ્રની જેમ વિશ્વમાં વ્યાપ છે&lt;br /&gt;
એવા અર્જુનની ઓળખ પૂછી કોઈએ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ના કીધું એણે કે હું અર્જુન&lt;br /&gt;
ના કીધું સર્વશ્રેષ્ઠ ધનુર્ધર&lt;br /&gt;
ના કીધું પાંડવ ના કોન્તેય&lt;br /&gt;
ના કહ્યું એણે કે મારી ઓળખ તો મારા દસ નામ&lt;br /&gt;
ના કૃષ્ણનો મિત્ર કહ્યો, ના ઇન્દ્ર નો વંશજ&lt;br /&gt;
ના એની ઓળખ ગાંડીવે આપી, ના પાશુપત અસ્ત્રએ&lt;br /&gt;
હર સમય હર સંજોગમાં એણે એજ કહ્યું કે&lt;br /&gt;
હું મારા ગુરુનો શિષ્ય અને એજ મારી ઓળખ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;એ અર્જુન તો મોટોભા થયો&lt;br /&gt;
એની સામે મારી શું વિસાત ને શું ઓળખ&lt;br /&gt;
પણ મને જો કોઈ મારી ઓળખ પૂછી લો&lt;br /&gt;
તો હું ભી એજ કહું કે&lt;br /&gt;
હું મારા ગુરુનો શિષ્ય અને એજ મારી ઓળખ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here it is, in English (courtesy Dharman Dave)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need an introduction&lt;br /&gt;
He whose prestige is known to the world like the moon&lt;br /&gt;
Someone asked that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arjuna&#34;&gt;Arjun&lt;/a&gt; his identity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither did he say I am (the famous) Arjun&lt;br /&gt;
Nor did he say I am the great archer (best of the best)&lt;br /&gt;
Neither did he say he was the son of Pandu&lt;br /&gt;
Nor the son of Kunti&lt;br /&gt;
He also didn’t say, “My identity is my ten names”&lt;br /&gt;
Neither did he say, “I’m a friend of (Lord) Krishna’s“&lt;br /&gt;
Nor a descendent of (God) Indra
Neither was he identified by Gandiv (indestructible bow)&lt;br /&gt;
Nor by the Pashupat weapon (destroyer arrow)&lt;br /&gt;
Every time and under all circumstances he said the same thing,&lt;br /&gt;
“I am a student of my teacher and that is my only identity”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Arjun is a legend&lt;br /&gt;
I am nothing compared to him, so is my identity&lt;br /&gt;
But if someone asks for my identity&lt;br /&gt;
I would also say the exact same thing,&lt;br /&gt;
“I am a student of my teacher and that is my only identity”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey in Search of Destination</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2015/03/journey-in-search-of-destination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2015/03/journey-in-search-of-destination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never thought I would make this public. I wrote long back for one of my dear cousin. It was relevant then. But it is more relevant now. One of my best friend, batch mate, college mate, colleague at one point of time, rommie is now moving to another country. With a aim to never looking back for all the good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nrezzzz&#34;&gt;Andrew Vyas&lt;/a&gt; this is for you. You are one of the friend I never wanted because I knew one day time flew and you or me will move on and that may be good for future but at point it is utterly painful. Pain that can&amp;rsquo;t be defined by words my friend. But still here are few words&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मंजिल की तलाश में दूर हम निकल गए &lt;br&gt;
रस्ते बनते गए हमराही मिलते गए&lt;br&gt;
मंजिल तोह आज भी दूर है&lt;br&gt;
मंजिल के लिए प्यार भी  वही है&lt;br&gt;
लेकिन पता नहीं क्यों रस्ते इतने अच्छे क्यों है&lt;br&gt;
आँखे इतनी नर्म क्यों है&lt;br&gt;
मंजिल पाने की चाह तो आज भी वही है&lt;br&gt;
हमराही को छोड़ने का गम क्यों है&lt;br&gt;
हमराही कल भी बिछड़े थे, आज भी बिछड़ रहे है&lt;br&gt;
लेकिन दील मे एक सन्नाटा, तन्हाई, दर्द आज ही क्यों है&lt;br&gt;
मंजिल की तलाश में हम तो फीर भी निकल चले है&lt;br&gt;
रस्ते फीर बनते चले है, हमराही फीर मिलते चले है&lt;br&gt;
लेकिन दील मै उनकी याद क्यों है, ये दर्द एक बेचैनी सि क्यों है&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For people who don&amp;rsquo;t understand Hindi, here is English translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In search of destination we came long way&lt;br&gt;
roads started carving them selves, new companion started joining me&lt;br&gt;
destination is still far&lt;br&gt;
love for destination is still there&lt;br&gt;
but don&amp;rsquo;t know why roads seems more beautiful&lt;br&gt;
and have tears at the corner of my eyes&lt;br&gt;
Desire to get to the destination is still the same&lt;br&gt;
then why there is pain for leaving companion back&lt;br&gt;
I left companion and I am leaving companion back&lt;br&gt;
then why there is silence, loneliness and pain in heart&lt;br&gt;
Still moving on in search of destination&lt;br&gt;
roads are being made again, companion are started joining again&lt;br&gt;
then why there are memories them of who left behind, why there is pain, restlessness in heart.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear friend wherever you go my wishes and prayers are always there for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to wonderful community</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few days back &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; tweeted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a moment, right now, and email the organizers of your favorite Open Source project and THANK THEM.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Scott Hanselman (@shanselman) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shanselman/statuses/456216661415034880&#34;&gt;April 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think, I should do that. But twitter is too short and emails boring even I don&amp;rsquo;t have email ids of few of my favourite Open Source project managers. But I am not shying away from thanking. So, I am writing this entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will try to cover as many person as possible who made important part in my life; mainly professionally and sometimes personally too. But if I miss someone, that will be completely unintentional and I am extremely sorry for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a little story. My life was nothing different then every other software engineer. I missed first class by .08% and get out of college in the era of recession. And technically know nothing but little bit of C#.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are pretty normal. Just like every other software person in Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/mu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All dreams and no way to achieve it. Then luckily or unluckily I move to company where I need to work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asp.net/mvc&#34;&gt;Asp.Net MVC&lt;/a&gt;. First thing I did was find something on home site. I don&amp;rsquo;t know there are still any archive available but at that time there is a video series by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wekeroad.com/&#34;&gt;Rob Conery&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know him by then or even his reputation. For me he is Microsoft employee and I am working in Microsoft Technology so he is God sent. Whatever he say is truth nothing but the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while wondering around his site, found the video he gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ndcoslo.com/&#34;&gt;NDC conference&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;strong&gt;The Next Big Thing Or Cool-Kid Koolaid? Slicing Through The Rhetoric of MVC vs Web Forms&lt;/strong&gt; . Sorry I didn&amp;rsquo;t found any downloadable link for it but I still do have a copy of it. This video changed me up side down, changed my way of thinking and learning. I started questioning more and learning more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way &lt;strong&gt;Rob&lt;/strong&gt; is responsible for my way to community. Then I became customer/viewer/admirer of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tekpub.com/&#34;&gt;tekpub&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Yes, I do earn in rupees and spend in dollars&lt;/em&gt;. but every penny of it is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best thing happen is; it opens the door of open source projects. Its all started with leaving EF and checking out other ORMs. I&amp;rsquo;ll not talk about them now, but will move to my few favourite web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is &lt;a href=&#34;http://servicestack.net/&#34;&gt;Servicestack&lt;/a&gt; and other is &lt;a href=&#34;http://nancyfx.org/&#34;&gt;NancyFX&lt;/a&gt;. I do like others but this are kinda first ones&amp;rsquo; I fall in love with. And just like first love nothing can replace that. I like to thank them for their work. Both are wonderful frameworks to do the web development if someone is working in the .Net. One is for rapid web development and other is rapid web service development in true to the nature of Object Oriented Programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is one more transaction of me from Object Oriented Programming to Functional Programming. Trust me the F# community is awesome and that is kind of reason behind the transaction. Don&amp;rsquo;t know why but they are simple awesome. And I love to thank them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am 1986 born, so I am kid to most of the member of the F# community. Most of them are coding even before the day I born. But whenever I stuck somewhere or something they help and give answer to any of my dumbest question. Thank You &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be not knowing philosophical programming without &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jessitron&#34;&gt;Jessica Kerr&lt;/a&gt;, will not be knowing Actors without &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rachelreese&#34;&gt;Rachele Resse&lt;/a&gt;,functional programming will not be fun without &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bodil&#34;&gt;Bodil&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s presentation/talks, without infinite force of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dsyme&#34;&gt;Don Syme&lt;/a&gt; there is no me &amp;lt;3 F# and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ptrelford&#34;&gt;Phillip Trelford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/7sharp9&#34;&gt;Dave Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ScottWlaschin&#34;&gt;Scott Wlaschin&lt;/a&gt; and others who are always there for community. I never meet any of them but they are always there whenever I need them. May be this is the reason Internet was invented, or if I say specifically then social network invented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry if I missed any other community members. But there is a long list. Hopefully someday I meet them and thank them in personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even this blog is running on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Sandra/Sandra.Snow&#34;&gt;Snow&lt;/a&gt; made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/philliphaydon&#34;&gt;Phillip Haydon&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks &amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I continue writing more poems?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/should-i-continue-writing-more-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/should-i-continue-writing-more-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long back I have tried my hand to writing poems. And trust me I am no where near poetic part. I have good grip over language but that is only for my mother tongue. I am quite comfortable with English but still no where near having artistic touch. Or in simple language my database of words is not that strong. But normally I am able to convey my feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say, I am pretty lucky in the case of writing poems. Though I have write only few, many of them got good review from whom so ever read it. But that charm doesn&amp;rsquo;t last that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a poem for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/&#34;&gt;sister&lt;/a&gt; and it don&amp;rsquo;t get any kind of review. I do got personal message from sister after a long time that &amp;ldquo;it was sweet&amp;rdquo;. But that all because she is my sister. Personally if I like to give review to my this poem it is not good at all. There are tsunami of feeling I wanted to convert and I just converted drops of it. And at that moment I decided, will never write poem; at least never in public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do write sometimes, but that is all personal on personal request. And I will not say that poem too. They are just few lines, I crafted for person requested. Like few hand picked words, that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But over the time I got request to write more poems. So, I decided to take a course at &lt;a href=&#34;https://class.coursera.org/songwriting-004&#34;&gt;coursera&lt;/a&gt; and with that I like to take opinion of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should I write more poems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please write whatever you think in comments. And help me to make a decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Business</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/back-to-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/08/back-to-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It have been long that I was doing active blogging. There are multiple reason for that, and on of them is being a lazy ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed my blog from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orchardproject.net&#34;&gt;Orchard&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://docpad.org/&#34;&gt;Docpad&lt;/a&gt; for almost no reason. I just wanted my few page look different then other pages. And that will little bit more effort if I am going to do it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orchardproject.net&#34;&gt;Orchard&lt;/a&gt;.  So, I check out on net how to do it. I know Rob was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://nestacms.com/&#34;&gt;Nesta&lt;/a&gt; but I am not good with Ruby, at least that much and more over ruby was giving issue on my windows machine. And switching on my VM just to write blog&amp;hellip; Naaaahhh!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I moved to Docpad. I have to loose some of my comments, which was there as part of Orchard system. But it was fine. Only painful thing is I have to do lot more work to just get it up as I wanted. It was not like set up and go using &lt;a href=&#34;http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-live/essentials&#34;&gt;Windows Essentials&amp;rsquo; Live Writer&lt;/a&gt;. But it is giving me flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in other reason, work load at day job. Things are moving faster then I can plan for. I was trying to learn other languages and tools. Moving out of my comfort zone. So, number of posts are less. Sadly!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also changed my job and my city, so that transaction do take time, specially leaving city like Bangalore was a bit of a pain on my side. Now, I am out shock, almost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But biggest lost I think, is my google juice. My site is not coming on front page if someone  search my name. Luckily I am and I was active on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kunjee&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; and it point to my site. So, still some juice stays there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I also owe apology to any readers who come to my site while I was modifying details, site was in bad state and I pushed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.heroku.com/&#34;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, that was total uncool of me. But there were some issue related to domain and I am to lazy to maintain production and master branch at least for my blog. I am the only one using it and I am not so popular; at least as of now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now things are far better than it was before. Site CSS is quite good and contents seems more readable. You can check it  out, comment and share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out blog entries. I am still changing things as I go but there will be no major changes. But do give me your suggestions if any regarding site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are still come even after this blog&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New home page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags for all blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags/Category pages to jump around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search page (damn simple google search, what else?!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Miss You Sister</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/04/i-miss-you-sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First friend I found was you&lt;br /&gt;
First enemy I found was you&lt;br /&gt;
First fight I had was with you&lt;br /&gt;
First person I always miss is you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beating me was your favorite game&lt;br /&gt;
Teasing me with different names&lt;br /&gt;
Remaining is now, only the pain&lt;br /&gt;
Not being with you, I feel mundane&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are Dad’s favorite&lt;br /&gt;
You are Mom’s favorite&lt;br /&gt;
But you know you are also my favorite&lt;br /&gt;
Then why you became someone else’s favorite&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Achievements are just made for you&lt;br /&gt;
Success always waiting for you&lt;br /&gt;
Even world is following you&lt;br /&gt;
But you know at home, someone still waiting for you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You went to school made new friends&lt;br /&gt;
You went to college made new friends&lt;br /&gt;
I go to school, you are my friend&lt;br /&gt;
I go to college, you are my friend&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you want to shine and never fade&lt;br /&gt;
Want to study and always be ahead&lt;br /&gt;
Want to work hard and move forward&lt;br /&gt;
But once look back, and then move forward&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time doesn’t stop, neither do you&lt;br /&gt;
You are busy with time for only few&lt;br /&gt;
I am still at doorstep, eagerly waiting for you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got married, had a new life&lt;br /&gt;
Few more smiles because of you,&lt;br /&gt;
A new sunrise shines your new life&lt;br /&gt;
But what will I do without you&lt;br /&gt;
I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life is incomplete without you&lt;br /&gt;
My poem is incomplete without you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss you, my dear sister&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bhagwad Gita Chapter 1</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;कुर्क्षेत्र की युद्ध भूमि पर सैन्य निरिक्षण&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its all started when war of Mahabharata is about to begin. Both army stand against each other. And at the time of war, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arjuna&#34;&gt;Arjuna&lt;/a&gt; told &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krishna&#34;&gt;Krishna&lt;/a&gt; to take his chariot to the middle of battle field. When they reach there, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arjuna&#34;&gt;Arjuna&lt;/a&gt; observed both side of army.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time he found only relatives on the both side. And he just collapsed. He don’t want to fight. He don’t want to win at the cost of killing his own relatives. He asked &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krishna&#34;&gt;Krishna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is significant of this type of win? Why should I win? Why should I do the war?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time Krishna recite Gita. Other than &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arjuna&#34;&gt;Arjuna&lt;/a&gt; there are few others who heard Gita, one is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanuman&#34;&gt;Hanuman&lt;/a&gt; who is there in the flag of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arjuna&#34;&gt;Arjuna’s&lt;/a&gt; chariot. And other is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanjaya&#34;&gt;Sanjay&lt;/a&gt; who has “divya drashti”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here by I try to explain every “slok” of Gita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pray to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ganesha&#34;&gt;Shree Ganesh&lt;/a&gt; as there is a tradition that every good thing start with the name of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ganesha&#34;&gt;Shree Ganesh&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bhagwad Gita Introduction</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/01/bhagwad-gita-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who ever know something about Indian culture must have know about Gita. As per religion or history whatever you prefer, it is a compilation of words, a message given to Arjuna by Krishna. It is not only for him but for whole world. And trust me this book do have answer of almost any things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I brief about this compilation. At the time of Mahabharata war, when Arjuna has to face his own family at war place, kurukshetra. He did not want to fight, he did not want to win at a price of killing his own loved once. At that time Shree Krishna, told him that it is his work, he is not responsible of it. He had to do what is necessary. He didn’t have any right to claim on result of his work. And then whatever communication is done between them is called Bhagwad Gita. Other than Arjuna there were few other who witnesses this communication, one is Ved Vyas who written Mahabharat, one is Sajay a Charioteer of King Dhitrashtra and Hanuman who was there in the flag of Chariot of Arjuna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a big philosopher or spiritual guru, but I love this book. And trying to explain each and every “slok”, sentence in detail. Please bare with me, if there is any mistake in understanding or explaining this .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t say I am a great believer of God, but I am believer of this book. It do has solution of every problem, and do support to over come any obstacle of life. Gita was told by Shree Krishna around 5000 years back and even now every word of it, is so true and real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few, who still believe the Shree Krishna is Myth, for them here I am sharing a video, just have a look at it. And I don’t mind any opinion but whats wrong in trying new things, and a thing which already had more than enough followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video about Krishna is here.
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/dalNJ4luBws&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DI of FDI (Foreign direct investment)</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/di-of-fdi-foreign-direct-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/di-of-fdi-foreign-direct-investment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a week or so, every day news paper and news channel are full with news of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/s18yeT&#34;&gt;FDI in India&lt;/a&gt; . Even Facebook is not taking a step back and speak in favor of both side. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign_direct_investment&#34;&gt;FDI&lt;/a&gt; in retails should be allowed or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a politician, so as engineer I will do data analysis of FDI in India. now, for the sake of example we consider that FDI is allowed in retail market (PS : I personally think that it is going to be allowed) . And great retail players welcomed, in India. Just like east India company. Now, dollars come in and they directly go to farmers to take products. Ohk… now here framers get a BIT more price as they skip mediators. Now, they are the immediate victims of FDI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have around 125 corers people and also have internal dependencies in chain management system. Now, for the sake of two end users, big brother will element man small chains and put one big heavy chain. Here, we can advocate that even a one big chain need many persons to work properly. So, we can say that it will generate more employment. We WILL discuss this specific topic afterwards, service v/s self employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, after first victim is down. We have a classis competition of dollars v/s rupees, its just like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goliath&#34;&gt;David v/s Goliath&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-UOYX0j4d74Y/URHJr5nw2nI/AAAAAAAAAqg/bmKB4tSWmoY/s144/david-and-goliath-sumo-version_thumb_2456faf3-4b48-4d31-8a4d-440692818ef1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They come with dollar back up, give best employment. Buy land at high price. Market go boom. And smile on the face of everyone, at least for a while. Yeah, some brokers and &lt;strong&gt;independent&lt;/strong&gt; businessmen, who were there in chain will not be happy. But who cares. Even from the era of non-violence and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mohandas_Karamchand_Gandhi&#34;&gt;Gandhiji&lt;/a&gt; we also learn one more thing to serve others. Specially &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_of_the_United_Kingdom&#34;&gt;British Culture&lt;/a&gt; and Foreigners. Sorry to some die hard fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mohandas_Karamchand_Gandhi&#34;&gt;Gandhiji&lt;/a&gt; but its true. He is there in direct or indirect reason of our slavery even after our so called freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now back to FDI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are getting things at low price. But missing one basic element of our shopping. Relationship with our merchant. So, here we are loosing personal guarantee of shop keeper. We have professional warranty of brand but what on grains???!!!! No one is saving seasonal vegetables for you. If you are lucky you get your favorite vegetables or if not you have to go with whatever is left there. But who cares !!! you are getting vegetables at lower prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, As an engineer and a little bit selfish person I should be happy???????&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why??? Now, consider a case of my favorite fruit Mango. And I love specific type of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mango&#34;&gt;Mango called Kesar&lt;/a&gt; ** and that also specifically from &lt;a href=&#34;http://meet-kesarmango.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Talala Gir area&lt;/a&gt; . Now, big brother is going to buy bulk from farmers. And going to sell at lower price. I don’t think so. They sell poor and small pieces of Mangos in India and better will go out side to be sold in foreign currency. I don’t think problem in this too, as we also get used to that. Just like we get used to poor quality of every international brand. We are so good and non-violent people at the end. We are from the country of Great Mahatma Gandhiji. (PS: yes, we are from the country of Gandhiji, but still Gujarat is the only dry state ???!!!! why don’t other states are following our great leader ???!!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now its time for us to suffer. Poor quality food, grains and vegetables. …. No problem at all, most of the metros are not getting good quality food even now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, time passes and we survived and life go on. All the small business men are vanished, cleared, wiped out. No competition at all. Now, big brother can increase price. And yet again we don’t mind. Yaar, we are good people na, at the max we will do some rally and that also non-violently. And our minister comment that “ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report_i-m-no-astrologer-can-t-predict-fall-in-prices-says-sharad-pawar_1333724&#34;&gt;I am not astrologer, how can I say what will going to happen in future&lt;/a&gt; .” And some remember &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bhagat_Singh&#34;&gt;Bhagat Singh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://articles.timesofindia.indiatimes.com/2011-11-25/india/30440409_1_anti-graft-protester-sharad-pawar&#34;&gt;hit a slap&lt;/a&gt; . But that also ended with &lt;strong&gt;BANDH&lt;/strong&gt; in oppose of that slap. It is fine we are in India…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, only one person is laughing and laughing laud our own the big brother. But still we will going to celebrate, as big brother will be in the list of Forbes richest person, give lecture at IIMs and comment that India is his favorite market. Why not??? he is selling every good product at high rate in foreign country and getting price of garbage in India. Double profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next big step, investment in farming. If everything is his, then why not farms. And government also welcome that, as they bring new technology to India (PS: what the hell, as don’t know anything about farming ???!!!!) . Obviously this will increase more employment , now farmers are employees too. And banned chemicals are welcomed to India, which increase growth for at least two years. So, time for some smiles now. But then farms are gone, quality goods are gone. And we left with dry land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No problem, we will &lt;strong&gt;Import&lt;/strong&gt; . And government will give subsidy in that. So, now India back to square one. Just it were at the time of 1857 (PS: Many so called urban and modern public don’t know this number, please &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/vhOUwG&#34;&gt;google&lt;/a&gt; it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still we have one smiling face of big brother. And books of him “How to Become a Millionaire” for future management students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, one topic I have left in the starting service v/s self employment. Now, first thing I am doing job and I am not opposing it. But self employment is also just like that. You are employed if you are earning enough as per your requirement and caliber. Serving some big brother will never make you jolly good fellow. In simple situation if some person is earning 3Rs as profit, he will give 1Rs as salary. Now, this 2Rs will made him more rich every time he earns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we take retail sector as per example, a person of transport is earning 12,000Rs per month. Now, there are 10 persons for specific city. So, total earning goes to 1,20,000. Now, big brother hire some around 5 persons and give 15,000Rs salary. So, total earning goes to 75,000Rs. Now, salary is higher for whom, those got the job. But for 5 persons, 10 persons loses their job and employment. And there is movement of only 75,000Rs instead of 1,20,000Rs. Now, a person from commerce background can explain the importance of the “movement of money”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one more thing is here to consider. If you or me go to some other country and earn some money, first thing we will do is to send money to our country. Same will be done by the big brother. Profit will be sent to his country. In history we were not poor, but now we are still a developing country. Even at this stage can we afford to send profit to some other country ???? I don’t think so. I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end still we have some happiness left. Big Brother is smiling and yes we have few more to join party. Our minister, AKA, sultan, Prince of country and his mom… Who are getting money for welcoming big brother and also take a part of profit as tax. And every one knows now in which country our tax is going ???!!!! (PS: As per &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chanakya&#34;&gt;Chankya&lt;/a&gt; tax should be taken in a way honey bee take honey from flowers)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so proud for my analytical and mathematical skills, but don’t have answer to this. If you have, please share… Do comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PS Are we going to be slaved again??? Is this the time where we should start asking question to us, our belief ??? Is this the time for change from the root, from the start???!!!!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot of Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/snapshot-of-steve-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/snapshot-of-steve-jobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was reading article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970203633104576620972142056528.html&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; , about Steve Jobs. It was wonderful article taken by Ralph, at time of starting phase of apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the time of change, if any one is familiar with the history of&amp;nbsp; computer world, must know the era of changing. When companies like Microsoft and Apple started and change the rule of game. They change the way of thinking that computer should be big and for co-operate work only. Computer should be good at calculation only, that black screen just calculate and give desire output to management. Person of industry wearing suits and showing standers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Than hippy like guys arrived, who break all the rule, and drive world to new future. Right now I want&amp;nbsp; to talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/stevejobs/&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt; . Who just left us, leaving behind the a legacy of change and revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every paragraph of article just showing attitude of Steve, never say never attitude, non-compromising mentality. Courage to take risk, and most important confidence in his own self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thing is completely opposite to Indian mentality, where we learn to compromise from the starting. Every time we are forced to change our self as per society. Many of us, just do something for the sake of doing. Earning money is important than earning credit. Confidence is just a short term certificate which we get at college as college result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not saying, I am different. But I can say, I am trying to be different. And one of person behind this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/stevejobs/&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt; . I know about him from my college days, but start understanding him after college. Whenever I fill down and out I hear him or read him, which always motivates me to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the person with still nerve. No matter whatever it takes, he will achieve what he want. I never seen a person like him. He is gem of crown of silicon-valley. Its not only he done for him self but inspire person like Mark who created &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.com/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; , bill gates of &lt;a href=&#34;http://microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not he hadn&amp;rsquo;t face downfall, everyone does in lifetime, but how he reacts is the real thing matters. I personally recommended that everyone directly or indirectly related to computer industry must watch movie Pirates of Silicon-Valley and go through the life of him. Also, can found video of him on &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>