<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dotnet on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</title>
    <link>http://kunjan.in/tags/dotnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dotnet on Kunjan&#39;s Web Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kunjan.in/tags/dotnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>To Xamarin with Love</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/to-xamarin-with-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/to-xamarin-with-love/</guid>
      <description>Xamarin Evolve just concluded. And there no best time to write this post. And for the fact I am not writing anything new or even anything related to announcements that happened there. I am writing this because recently I got chance to work with android using Java. And experience was not at all good. And reason is not so surprisingly Java.
I am will not explain anything instead I just copy paste three code snippets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web programming and F# still a Far Cry?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/10/web-programming-and-fsharp-still-a-far-cry/</guid>
      <description>F# is wonderful language. And luckily or unluckily I do Web Programming (now a days mostly that). So, it is always a preference to use it, wherever possible. But even in 2014 end it is still pain in a**.
I did make templates for Servicestack and I will continue to support that. But when it comes to real projects they go far beyond templates.
I recently experimenting on something and obviously I am gonna use templates created by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My broken marriage with C# and extramarital affair with F#</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/my-broken-marriage-with-csharp-and-extramarital-affair-with-fsharp/</guid>
      <description>*NOTE- As per today I am neither married nor committed. And for that case never married and never committed. :P*
 Whoever is following my progress must be knowing my love for F#. Neither me nor F# knows exact time and date when that happen. But now it is like if few days I have to pass without writing few lines to(in) F# then it felt like I have left software engineering for good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Servciestack with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/signalr-servicestack-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>This may be nastiest thing I have done with deployment after a long time. There is no problem with making it work. But deployment on azure is a serious issue. And luckily I completed that. Yes, there is a luck involved.
If you read my previous entry for running Nancy and SignalR together. Then most of the things are same only.
Use Servicestack template to create project. Remove global.asax &amp;amp; global.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xamarin Studio 3 - First Look</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamarin-studio-3---first-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/06/xamarin-studio-3---first-look/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I got mail from Xamarin about their launch of new IDE. And also for the registration of webinar. And just like always they again managed to blow my mind. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what else they are having for upcoming evolve conference..
Xamarin is like technical democracy. &amp;gt; A company of Technical People, by the technical people and for the technical people.
A kinda awesome. Just like their new studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to wonderful community</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/04/thanks-to-wonderful-community/</guid>
      <description>Few days back Scott Hanselman tweeted
Take a moment, right now, and email the organizers of your favorite Open Source project and THANK THEM.
&amp;mdash; Scott Hanselman (@shanselman) April 15, 2014 
And I think, I should do that. But twitter is too short and emails boring even I don&amp;rsquo;t have email ids of few of my favourite Open Source project managers. But I am not shying away from thanking. So, I am writing this entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SignalR &#43; Nancy with F# hosted on Azure</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/signalr-nancy-with-fsharp-hosted-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>What you feel if you meet your favourite actor? Feeling is wonderful right? Now, add the your actress in the mixture. Have you said WOW??? How about director? Still heart is beating?!? How about having dinner with them? Nothing can be better than that.
I am having kinda same feeling. It is nothing new that Nancy is dancing quite comfortable with F#. And thanks to Daniel Mohl we are also having templates to get started with Nancy and F#.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I moved away from Sencha to Phonejs?</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/03/why-i-moved-away-from-sencha-to-phonejs/</guid>
      <description>Sencha is well known framework for mobile development. Not only mobile development but it is doing a hell of a lot of thing other than mobile development. Not only that it is surely having wonderful history with JavaScript framework development. I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to complain against that.
But today I am going to talk about specifically one framework, that is Sencha Touch. I was trying to something that can developed once and deployed everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servicestack F# template. Starting from the Start</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-starting-from-start/</guid>
      <description>I have already wrote a blog post about how to get started with service stack if any one is using templates. It is pretty easy. Just install and run.
But as Service Stack is moved to V4 with some breaking changes. I had give details about updating it. But still it is little bit more complicated or confusing if I can say.
@kunjee Sure, otherwise a tutorial on getting SS v4 + F# together without templates would be better than starting from a broken v3 one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servicestack F# template Update. Circle is Complete</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-update-circle-is-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2014/02/servicestack-fsharp-template-update-circle-is-complete/</guid>
      <description>Few day&amp;rsquo;s back I wrote a article about how I created side waffle templates for Servicestack.
Yesterday, Daniel Mohl, merged the pull request. Add the missing bits make it working and it is up on visual studio gallery. I seriously like to thank Daniel for this work and support even after his own hectic schedule of day job. And a wonderful members of F# community.
Here, I am sharing few details of the template, I have created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming Need in Web Development</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2013/12/functional-programming-need-in-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2013/12/functional-programming-need-in-web-development/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I talk about Functional Programming people with experience in web make faces. And seriously don&amp;rsquo;t blame them.
Issue is mainly Functional Programming stays in back ground only. If you see any starting example of any functional language is mainly some machine learning example or some complicated algorithm example. And that may effect normal people to getting started with Functional Programming.
But functional programming can do far more than that. And that include simple things too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entity Framework Upside Down</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/12/entity-framework-upside-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/12/entity-framework-upside-down/</guid>
      <description>If you have read my previous articles you must be knowing that I don’t like ORMs that much and also I am pretty lazy person. I don’t like to repeat stuff again and again. If I can find the solution than I will automate it or I just change from very root. Same thing is true with Entity Framework. It comes after LINQ to SQL as an improved ORM. And it proved to be lousy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Never Changed!!! Guiding Principles to Software Development</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/11/something-never-changed-guiding-principals-to-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/11/something-never-changed-guiding-principals-to-software-development/</guid>
      <description>I am particularly a lazy guy. I don’t work hard, stay back and never show sad face to issue or bug. Obviously many don’t like me for this. But again “who cares?”. But one thing is sure for me, I always ready to learn new things and obviously always work for better code. At the end of day it is just a code, bugs will be there and me too , to solve the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duffer&#39;s guide for windows 8 installation</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/duffers-guide-for-windows-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/duffers-guide-for-windows-installation/</guid>
      <description>Oops, I used “Duffer” instead of “Dummy” because I am one of it.
I installed OS nearly 8 times to get what I wanted from Windows 8. I brought new Dell Ultra book and first thing I have done is to install consumer preview, second thing installing VS2012. And I meet my first issue, it is not allowed so I need to use trial version, so another format and new OS in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type Casting JavaScript with Typescript</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/type-casting-javascript-with-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/10/type-casting-javascript-with-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Whenever something came from Microsoft or Microsoft employee there is always a buzz… And I still don’t understand why person’s company policies do with person’s attitude or approach of a person. Same happens when typescript came. It was just a day old and Open Source People starts bashing it like anything. Comparing with CoffeeScript , Dart . Guys, it is also open source and Microsoft in any case not forcing anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive Effect</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/massive-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/massive-effect/</guid>
      <description>Hope you have read my earlier post about Micro ORM . Here I talk about another Micro ORM Massive . I don’t want to go with traditional approach. I write intro about Rob Conery and give some details about Massive . Few example here and there, some hyperlinks and that’s it. I will try to find answer of “why” instead of “how”. For how part we have more than enough example and also have stackoverflow to solve issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrival of David aka Micro Orm</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/arrival-of-david-aka-micro-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/arrival-of-david-aka-micro-orm/</guid>
      <description>If you have read my previous post . I have talk about how ORM can create mess with the application. And prior to that I have write that it speed up the production like anything.
 So, Am I contradicting my self ???
 No, I am just learning new things. I am using ORM but now I am more careful while using it. That’s it.
 So, why Vietnam ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to Vietnam Because of ORM</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/going-to-vietnam-because-of-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/going-to-vietnam-because-of-orm/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I have talk about ORM . But believe if you don’t use thing wisely you are going to fall like anything. In this article I am not going to write any code but still it is a pure technical article. I will talk about enterprise application and how quickly love for ORM will drag you to the black hole.
Around two years back, at the time when .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map your self using ORM</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/map-your-self-using-orm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/map-your-self-using-orm/</guid>
      <description>Many of you must know this word, “ORM”. Then why this post. But trust, even after we have a lots and lots of ORMs in market and some company still using age old technology. Just few days back in one company again I had to face same old question about connection class and command class. Why?????????? It is so true that one must know that things, but this question is always be a nightmare to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuget mall of OSS</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/nuget-mall-of-oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2012/02/nuget-mall-of-oss/</guid>
      <description>OSS, stands for Open Source Software. If you are a .net developer, most of the time you don’t care much of OSS. But trust me, OSS are far better than pure solution provided by MS.
And now MS is pushing for OSS, via nuget . It’s a wonderful site providing base for OSS technologies. If you have experienced development in Ruby, you must have known this. Ruby has gems, which pushed by open source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test your self before test your code</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/test-your-self-before-test-your-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/12/test-your-self-before-test-your-code/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I had written a post , on Test Driven Development . And many of my friends raise question, why should I test and is there anything there in built in Visual Studio. And also more explanation on Test Driven Design. So, Here again I will some what more deeper in testing. Ok, its just a little bit deeper.
First thing, as per title, you should test your self before test your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOA Service Oriented Architecture Beginning of New Era</title>
      <link>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/soa-service-oriented-architecture-beginning-of-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kunjan.in/2011/10/soa-service-oriented-architecture-beginning-of-new-era/</guid>
      <description>Web services is not new to computer world, it is in use from long back. But now a day, with electronic revolution we have lot more devices with loaded application. We want everything everywhere. We need access of facebook from PC, from mobile, from Tablet.
Everyone has more than one email id, and want to be online at once.Chatting with friends on gmail , hotmail , aol , yahoo , ICQ , facebook , linkedin and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>